他说4分钟 多一秒少一秒都不行
He said four minutes precisely.
不 不 不
Non, non, non.
再拿两个来 快点
Quickly.
这次的鸡蛋应该很完美了吧
Two perfect eggs this time, no?
也许吧
Maybe.
看来是鸡的错
I blame the chicken.
母鸡下蛋时候没有算好尺寸
Why do hens lay eggs of different sizes?
这不是你的错
It's not you, mon ami.
这两个鸡蛋很完美
These are two perfectly good oeufs.
波洛先生
Mr. Poirot...
三名神职人员都带来了
I've got three religions bent on riot.
您准备好大显身手的话
If you're going to perform one of your miracles,
现在是时候了
the time is now.
鸡蛋你留着吃 我们走
Have the eggs. Allons-y!
波洛
Poirot!
抱歉 你踩到了
Sorry for the, um...
问题并不在于
It is not the, uh...
而是在于一种不平衡感
It is the imbalance of the...
是的
Right.
好多了
That's better.
借过 让我们过去
Excuse me. Coming through.
请让一让
Make way, please. Excuse me.
把三名嫌疑犯都带上来
Please call for the accused.
拉比
The rabbi...
神父
the priest...
伊玛目
and the imam.
是不是很像以前的一个笑话
It is like the old joke, yes?
拉比 神父 伊玛目
The rabbi, the priest, and the imam.
请见谅 我是比利时人
Forgive me, I am Belgian.
那开始吧
So, let us begin.
就在这里的圣墓大教堂里面
In the Church of the Holy Sepulchre above us...
我们的三位代表
three representatives meet under the supervision...
在总督察的监督下进行了会面
of the Chief Inspector of Police
为了商讨轮流使用集市的时间表
to discuss a divided timetable for market use.
紧张的会面结束一小时后
One hour after this tense meeting...
教堂里一件价值连城的文物被偷了
a priceless relic is found to be stolen.
有人说 小偷就在 这三个人之中
It is said, one of these three men has stolen it.
警方至今未能找到任何证据
The police find no pieces of evidence at all.
而我找到了一个
I find one.
证据就在教堂内保存完好的壁画上
On the meticulously well-kept wall of a fresco...
一道细微的裂痕 应该是一个
a single crack from an indelicate climb...
穿着硬底鞋或者靴子的人 在笨手笨脚攀爬时留下
with a hard-soled shoe or perhaps a boot.
那么 在场的各位一定会问
So, ladies and gentlemen, we must ask...
谁是此案中最大的受益者呢
who stands to benefit from the crime.
我们的三位神职人员 生活简朴
Our three holy men live humbly.
他们买不起这么高档的鞋子
They're thin-soled shoes poor.
突如其来的金银财宝
Sudden riches and rubies would be...
对他们来说太显眼了 不是吗 他们根本无福消受
too conspicuous, yes, to enjoy. They do not gain.
此时我需要一个警卫去守住南门
At this point, we need an armed guard at the south gate.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
所以唯一
No, the only one...
能在这次偷盗事件中 以及事件所产生的骚乱中获益的人
who benefits from the theft and the unrest it causes...
我今早已经派人搜过他的办公室了
is a man whose office I had searched this morning...
当时我正在等早餐
as I waited, I have to tell you,
说实话 我对那顿早餐很失望
rather disappointedly upon my breakfast.
是鸡蛋的问题 我就不细说了
Difficulty with eggs. You don't need to know this.
此人拿着丰厚的薪水 来维持耶路撒冷的秩序
A man who is paid lavishly to keep order in Jerusalem.
我说的那个人
I mean, of course,
就是我们的总督察
the Chief Inspector of the Police.
当他听到周围的民众
A man who does not wish to lose a well-paid post...
都嚷嚷着要自治
when there is discussion
他就害怕自己会失去这份高薪职位
among the local peoples of self-governance...
这个人穿得起靴子 而且我相信
who does wear boots, and who, I believe, now does regret...
他现在一定很后悔 请我来调查这起案件
inviting me to consult on this case.
你竟敢这么污蔑我
How dare you accuse me!
麻烦你警官
Please, Sergeant...
按照我说的搜过他的办公室了吗
did you search the office as I asked?
是的 先生
Uh, yes, sir.
有找到我和你说的那样东西吗
And did you find what I said you might?
是的 先生 就是您所说的那个
Uh, yes, sir. Just as you said.
谢谢
Merci.
站住
Halt!
需要你送过去
You need to deliver that, Captain.
明早第一批就送过去
It should be through first thing in the morning.
很好 先生
Very good, sir.
您的行李都装好了 先生
Luggage is on board, sir.
很荣幸能送您上船
I won the right to escort you to your boat.
去伊斯坦布尔吗
To Stamboul, then?
然后直接回伦敦吗
Will you be back to London straight off?
我有点儿累了 所以想给自己放一个长假
I am tired, and I have earned myself a little holiday.
想去看看画展
I want to look at paintings
反正有的是时间
and have too much time on my hands.
你一直盯着我看 有什么事么
You are staring. Does it stop?
我只是
It's just...
您怎么知道是他干的
How did you know it was him, sir?
就凭墙上的那条细缝吗
From just a tiny crack on the wall.
我这人有一个天赋
I have the advantage...
我的眼里只容得下真实的世界
I can only see the world as it should be.
即使是很小的瑕疵都会变得特别显眼
And when it is not, the imperfection stands out...
就像脸上的鼻子那样
like the nose in the middle of a face.
这会让生活变得无法忍受
It makes most of life unbearable.
但在办案的时候倒是非常有帮助
But it is useful in the detection of crime.
感觉您能看穿他们的心思
But it's as though you see into their hearts
探知他们的本性
and divine their true natures.
不管人们说了什么
And whatever people say,
要么是对的 要么是错的
there is right, there is wrong.
没有灰色地带
There is nothing in between.
就送到这儿吧
We must part here.
不 先生 我得送你上船
Oh, no, sir, I'm to escort you on the ferry.
再见了上尉
Au revoir, mon capitaine.
我们可能不会再见了
We must never meet again.
能不能麻烦你把领带摆正一点
Could you straighten your tie, please? Just a little.
好的 很完美
Yes. That is perfect.
请所有乘客上船
Final passengers, please!
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
很快就修好了
Will be fixed soon.
能及时修好吗
But, will it be fixed in time?
我们在想办法
We are working!
我要去伊斯坦布尔转火车
I have a connection in Stamboul.
明天7点发车
Leaves tomorrow at seven.
有一个重病患者还在伦敦等着我
There's a very ill patient waiting for me in London.
我是名医生
I am a doctor.
医生
Doctor.
我是一名医生
I am a doctor.
我居然用英文冲着你们喊
I am shouting at you in English,
嗓门那么大 还说的那么慢
and now I'm doing it louder and slower.
我真蠢 请见谅
Very silly, forgive me.
要帮忙吗 让我来吧
May I help? Let me help.
我认得你的胡子
I know your mustache.
我在报纸上见过
From the papers.
你是名侦探 赫拉克勒斯·波洛
You're the detective, Hercules Poirot?
我叫赫尔克里·波洛 你说的那位是杀死狮子的大力神
Hercule Poirot. I do not slay the lions. Mademoiselle.
名字我可能记错了
Mary Debenham, monsieur.
但脸不会错
I'll forget a name but never a face.
至少你的脸我不会记错
Not yours, anyway.
你是从巴格达来的吗
You come from Baghdad?
看来那些传闻是真的 什么都瞒不过您的眼睛
It's true. No detail escapes his notice.
票上写着呢
Your ticket. Ah.
我还想问您在那儿当家庭教师
I might also ask you if you enjoyed your time there...
还算愉快吧
as a governess?
您袖口上的粉笔灰还有您的地理读物
The chalk on your sleeve and the geography primer.
不是家庭教师就是地图测绘员 我猜了一个
A governess or a cartographer. I made my gamble.
我一般喜欢从地理教起
I always begin them with geography...
然后逼着学生们把全世界都装到脑子里去
and monster them till they have the world down cold.
生活中可以迷失方向
They may get lost in life...
但不知道自己在哪儿可不行
but I'll be damned if they don't know where they are.
障碍清除了 时间刚刚好
Well, our chains are free. Right on time.
在海上的感觉真是自由啊
I feel so free out here on the water.
可惜我没有这个心情
I wish I could enjoy it.
- 我们应该退出 玛丽
We should be out of this, Mary.
- 现在不行
Not now.
等一切都结束了
When it's all over.
事成之后
When it's done.
就没有人能阻碍我们了
Then, nothing can touch us.
我的假期即将从这儿开启
Ah, my holiday begins here.
我能从这些朴实的烤饼里 窥探到这座城市的灵魂
I can see the soul of the city in these humble breads.
这个世界不断地走向毁灭 而在这儿
The world insists on destruction, yet here...
每天都有新鲜出炉的大师之作
masterpieces are baked to order every day.
波洛先生
Monsieur Poirot!
穆罕默德
Mohammed!
穆罕默德 我的朋友
Mohammed, my friend...
你真是个艺术家
you are an artist.
我的朋友
Ah! My friend!
抱歉
Sorry.
过来 过来
Here. Come, come.
别介意 我们只想
Don't mind us, we're just looking
找个地方谈点私事
for a place to have a private argument.
大概也就二十来分钟吧
It should take some 20 minutes or so...
等我们谈妥了
at which point we will both
或者至少我满意了就行
come to an agreement, or at least I will.
- 布克先生 - 波洛
Monsieur Bouc!
居然在厨房里见到你
Poirot! In the kitchen?
好吧 这位先生嗅探
Well, of course, this man will sniff out
美味酥饼的速度
a perfect pastry faster than he catches...
比他抓珠宝大盗的速度更快
a jewel thief.
我亲爱的朋友
Mon ami!
我现在不是警探了
Now, I am no longer a policeman.
你再犯事的话可没人捞你出来
I cannot bail you out when this goes badly, eh?
这位是我的老朋友 受人敬仰的波洛
This is my dear, old friend, the esteemed...
他出名前我们就认识了 而这位是
Poirot, who I knew before the esteem.
波洛 这位是
Hercule Poirot, this is...
- 一个妓女 - 是的
A prostitute. She is.
说的对 布克 你从没提过你有这么有名的朋友
I am. Bouc, you did not tell me you had famous friends.
我们之所以是朋友
We're friends because
就是因为我从不过问他案子上的事
I'm the only person who never asks him...
因为我根本就不在乎
any questions about his cases, because I don't care.
而他也从不嫌弃我人品差
And he never judges me for being a terrible person.
确实很差
Indeed you are.
女士 布克 一起喝一杯如何
Madame, Bouc, please join me for a drink, yes?
我只能陪你一小时
You only have me for an hour.
我还要赶7点的东方快车
I ride on the Orient Express at seven,
我是他们公司的董事
official director business.
我叔叔出高薪聘请我
Uncle pays me absurdly
让我在他豪华的列车上工作
to stay onboard his gorgeous train...
离他的办公室
and far away from him...
远远的
at the home office...
置身于觥筹交错
consigned to wine and dine
美人权贵之中
handsome officials for all eternity.
裙带关系也是门艺术
There is an art to nepotism.
你在这方面可是大师
And you are its Michelangelo!
波洛先生
Mr. Poirot.
你也是妓女吗
Are you a prostitute as well?
当然不是
Certainly not.
这家伙打扰到你了吗
Is this man bothering you?
快了
He is about to.
你是英国领事馆的人
You are from the British consulate.
没错 先生 是关于卡斯纳的案子
I am, sir. It is the Kassner case.
您怎么知道
Why, yes.
我的猜测是对的吗
I was correct in certain predictions?
准确无误
Quite.
我不需要读这份电报
I do not need to read the telegram.
真有趣
Oh, how fun.
是有人出轨了还是死了
Did someone cheat, or die?
很不幸 两者都是
Unfortunately, both.
有人
Someone has...
搅乱了我期待已久的假期
interrupted my longing for rest.
看来我今晚得和你一起走了 布克
It appears that I must travel with you tonight, Bouc.
能给我在东方快车上找个包厢吗
Can you find me a cabin on the Orient Express?
我的朋友
My friend...
别的我不敢说 大冬天里
I may not be good for much, but I sure as hell
在我的列车上
can get you a bed on my train...
给你找个床铺绝不成问题 三天行程
in the dead of winter. Three days...
让你无忧无虑 不用想着那些罪案了 你会喜欢的
free of care, concern or crime. You will love it.
女士 很高兴认识你
Mademoiselle, it has been a pleasure. Sir.
您的行李已经取走了
Your luggage has been collected
路费也已经付了
and your expenses paid.
您坐到加来下车
You will be met at Calais...
有人会送您到多佛
and then escorted to Dover,
然后再坐火车到伦敦维多利亚车站
and then by rail to London Victoria.
请允许我郑重地向您表达
I would like to formally
请别再说了
express gratitude. Please, don't speak.
越说越烦
You make it worse.
这是给你的小费 伙计 - 谢谢 马奎兹先生
Here's a tip for you, pal. Thank you, Mr. Marquez.
我都没帮你搬行李
I didn't even carry your luggage.
这一周我过得很愉快
Oh, I had a good week.
走运的时候就得庆祝
We celebrate when fortune smiles,
好运就得拿来分享
and we share the good fortune.
记得多说说我们美国人的好话
Remember to say nice things about us Americans, huh?
不
No!
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!
晚上好 先生
Monsieur, bonsoir.
雷切特先生
For you, Mr. Ratchett,
为您准备了我们这儿最好的位置
the best table in the house.
就在这儿 先生 最好的座位
Just here, sir. The very best table.
不 我要坐那边
No, I want that one.
嗨 马斯特曼 都安排妥了
Hey, Masterman. You got everything?
那还用问吗 麦奎因先生
Kind of you to inquire, Mr. MacQueen.
我从来不会出差错
I do not make mistakes.
我的天呐 是安德烈伯爵
Oh, my goodness! It's Count Andrenyi.
快来 快来
Come, come, come.
我在蒙特克里斯托看过您的舞蹈
I saw you dance at the Monte Cristo.
我能给您拍张照吗
Could I take your photograph?
别 别打脸
Please, my face, no!
抱歉
Sorry.
新普伦东方快车
The Simplon Orient Express...
经停索非亚 尼什 贝尔格莱德 温科夫齐 布罗德
with stops in Sofia, Niš, Belgrade, Vinkovci, Brod...
可中转至布加勒斯特 萨格勒布
with transfers to Bucharest, Zagreb,
的里雅斯特 威尼斯 米兰 洛桑
Trieste, Venezia, Milan, Lausanne...
第戎 巴黎 布伦 加来
Dijon, Paris, Boulogne, Calais...
可接驳前往多佛及伦敦
with connection to Dover and London,
列车十五分钟后发车
leaves in fifteen minutes!
过来 米歇尔 有贵客来了
This way, Michel! Precious cargo.
我要一间头等包厢
I need a first-class compartment.
好好照顾我的朋友
Give special care to my friend, Michel.
要像熊猫一样的国宝级待遇
I want him pampered like a zoo panda.
可是布克先生 席位已经满了
But Monsieur Bouc, we are fully booked.
没位置了
There's no space left.
想办法腾出来 可以安排11号包厢
Then we make space. He can have the number eleven.
那里一般都安排给政府人员
The eleven is always kept open for official use.
非常舒适
It's very comfortable.
11号有人了
Eleven is taken.
两天前一名奥地利教授定的
The Austrian professor booked it two days ago.
整趟列车就找不到
There is not one first-class
一个头等包厢吗
sleeper car on the whole train?
是的 先生
Negative, sir.
- 二等舱呢 - 一个空位都没有
Second-class? There's no space left at all.
德贝汉小姐
Mademoiselle Debenham.
波洛先生 您也坐这趟列车吗
Mr. Poirot, are you joining us?
那得看他们俩谁说得赢谁
It depends who wins this debate.
所有的乘客都到了吗
Have all the passengers arrived?
还差一位 哈里斯先生
All but one. Mr. Harris.
所有乘客
"All passengers must check in
至少提前半小时检票
"at least one half hour prior to time of departure...
否则座位可能被收回
"or their seat may be forfeit."
已经不到半小时了 收回座位
The half hour has passed. The seat is forfeit.
请把波洛先生的行李
Please take Monsieur Poirot's luggage
送到3号包厢 和麦奎因先生一间
to number three with Mr. MacQueen.
谢谢 布克 - 旅途愉快
Merci, Bouc. Enjoy, my friend.
欢迎您先生 谢谢
Welcome, sir. Merci.
数字3可不吉利
Number three is unlucky.
抱歉女生 刚才无意冒犯
Apologies, madame. I meant no disrespect.
偶尔冒犯一下也没关系
Well, you could try to mean a little.
坐火车出行
One thing about train travel,
难免会碰到一些人
you're always knocking into somebody.
那样才有趣
It's wonderful.
不过我还是想回去
Though, I am looking forward to getting back.
我爱旅行 辛辣的美食 异域风情 浪漫的邂逅是不错
Travel is fine for spicy food, mosques, meeting men.
但到头来还是自己的床最舒服
But eventually, you just miss your own bed.
肯定有人会说我总是满世界地找老公
I've been accused of husband hunting abroad.
不过我还真不否认这点
Well, I can't, in all honesty, deny it.
虽然我喜欢独处 我是说真的
I like my time alone, I do.
不过 一个女人如果有点钱的话
But a lady has certain needs
她的需求就该被满足
that deserve to be met if she has any money...
最好还是定期满足
and preferably, on a regular basis.
天呐 厨房着火了
Oh, my! Fire in the kitchen!
再会了 女士
Farewell, madame.
晚上好
Good evening.
Bonsoir.
9号包厢
Number nine.
晚上好
Good evening. Bonsoir, bonsoir.
你好吗 晚上好
How you doing? Bonsoir.
不好意思
Oh. Excusez-moi.
没事 你先请
No, after you.
谢谢
Merci, merci.
三号到了
Ah number three.
你是麦奎因先生吗
You are Mr MacQueen?
是的 我想你走错包厢了
Yeah. I think you might have the wrong berth.
抱歉 你有什么事吗 先生
Sorry, is there a problem sir?
不 没事
No, no problem.
列车满了
The train is full.
我想我们得当一回 怎么说来着 室友
I think that we are, how do you say... "bunkies."
是吗
Really?
我也感到很失望 这儿还不错
I am equally disappointed in you. This is nice.
快来 小宝贝们
Come along, darlings.
不行
No.
这间呢
This?
怎么行李还没送来
Why am I not yet unpacked?
五分钟后发车
Five minutes to departure.
最后一次通知乘客
Final call for passengers!
我们要不要给你梳毛啊
Shall we brush you?
他们动作怎么这么慢
What the hell is taking them so long?
发车后让他们赶紧铺床
Soon as we get out of here, have them make up the bed.
都安排好了 雷切特先生
It's already arranged, Mr. Ratchett.
不 先把床铺好 把我的录音机拿来
No, I want the bed made. And bring my Dictaphone.
连狗都上桌了
Dogs on the table.
真是我见过最恶心的事
Most disgusting thing I've ever seen in my life.
是的 先生 你去找麦奎因
Yes, sir. I want you to get MacQueen...
让他把米兰那笔买卖的单据全都拿来
and have him bring every receipt from the Milan sale.
现在就去 好的先生
I want you to get it done. Yes, sir.
- 马上就去
I want you to get it done now.
不是让你马上就去吗 - 马上 先生
Did I say get it done now? Right away, sir.
你最好小心点
"Better watch yourself."
您的咖啡 雷切特先生
Your coffee, Mr. Ratchett.
是谁干的
Who did this?
我不知道
I can't say, sir.
晚上好 哈伯德夫人
Good evening, Mrs. Hubbard.
你好 马斯特曼
Hello there, Mr. Masterman.
你好 女士
Well, hello.
你再这么看下去 我就要收费了
Eyes linger any longer, I'll have to charge rent.
我很乐意付钱
I'll pay.
继续喝吧
Mmm. Have another drink.
让您不高兴了吗
Are you insulted?
失望罢了
Hmm. Disappointed.
有些人是长得不错
Some men have a good look.
他们只要能够做到
All they have to do is...
闭上嘴
keep their mouth shut,
就能得到他们想要的
and they can take home any prize they want.
可惜他们偏偏做不到这点
Still, the mouth opens.
没事吧 哈伯德夫人
Is everything all right, Mrs. Hubbard?
我觉得您的直觉非常敏锐
You have a strong intuition, I know.
我第二任丈夫也这么说过
My second husband used to say just so.
等等 应该是第一任
Hold that, it was my first.
没错
Yeah.
他是我见过最聪明的男人
Brightest man I ever met.
长得像萝卜 不过我也爱过那颗萝卜
Face like a turnip, but I loved that turnip.
和您聊天很愉快
It was nice to talk.
晚安
Good night.
波洛先生
Monsieur Poirot?
请进 米歇尔
Entrez, Pierre Michel.
您醒了
Voilà.
晚餐时
When you take supper...
我会把麦奎因先生的东西
I will move Monsieur MacQueen
搬到布克先生的包厢
into Monsieur Bouc's compartment.
您享受头等舱待遇
You travel first class, monsieur.
太棒了 谢谢
Ah, impeccable. Merci.
用餐愉快
Bon appétit.
下午好
Good afternoon.
哈伯德夫人
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard.
下午好
Good afternoon.
请慢用
There we are.
敬我们乘坐的东方快车
Compliments of the Orient Express.
谢谢 布克先生
Thank you, Mr. Bouc.
有什么需要 随时告诉我
I am here for all of your needs.
不 谢谢 我不喝酒
No, thank you. I do not drink.
您不能喝酒吗
It does not agree with you?
我只是想远离罪孽
Sin does not agree with me.
恶习永远都是魔鬼的温床
Vice is where the devil finds his darlings.
那我就不打扰您了
We should no longer speak.
下午好
Good afternoon.
先生 要不要来杯开胃酒
Monsieur. How about a apéritif?
可惜我已经和火车上的负责人
I regret I have an appointment
约好了见面
with the director of the train.
他很快就要走了
He was gonna leave anyway.
没事 先生
Please, sir. Madame, madame.
女士 女士
Madame, madame.
都安顿好了吗
All settled in?
一切如广告所说
Ah, merci! As advertised.
不过 车上最好的可不是食物
And yet, the best things on the train are not food.
这实际上 就是
You know there's something about...
一群陌生人机缘巧合地坐上了同一趟列车
a tangle of strangers pressed together
一待就是几天
for days on end, with nothing in common...
除了这点之外 他们毫无关联
but the need to go from one place to another...
下车后就再也不见
then never to see each other again.
闲来无聊加上萍水相逢
Boredom plus anonymity plus a...
再配上不间断的晃动
constant, gentle rocking.
就你这样很难成大事
With your hobbies, you will never amount to anything.
我倒希望是这样
God, I hope so. Hmm.
给我点一道鱼
Order me the fish.
把石斑鱼换成比目鱼
Um, exchange grouper for sole,
再把莴苣换成土豆
escarole for the potato, and...
还有 牛肉汁换成白汁
the beef sauce for the velouté.
服务员 这听上去很棒 给我也来一份
Garçon, that sounds superb. The same for me.
德拉戈米罗夫公主
The Princess Dragomiroff.
如果我为了钱和人结婚
You know, if I ever were to marry for money,
就找她这么有钱的
I'd marry for that much money.
早上我给达莉娅梳了毛
I brushed Dalia this morning.
不 我让你给我的小狗梳毛
No, you tortured my darling doggy.
你却在折磨她
I asked you to brush her.
你还是爱看狄更斯的书吗
Are you still enjoying your Dickens?
当然了 我的朋友
Very much, mon ami.
你这样光顾着看书和破案
You know, with your books and your capers,
很容易就错过艳遇
you are missing out on romance.
艳遇永远都要付出代价
Romance never goes unpunished.
我以前
There was, uh...
也爱过一个人
There was someone once.
我希望之后别再让我坐在那个人旁边了
I would prefer, in the future, to be sat not with that man.
物以类聚 人以群分
Like should be seated with like.
我们并不是一类人
We are not alike.
不是所有人都会
Not all of us are so concerned
那么在意种族隔离 教授
with the separateness of races, Professor.
我的坚持完全是
It is out of respect for all kinds
出于对所有种族的尊重
that I prefer to keep them separate.
如果把红酒和白酒混在一起
To mix your red wine and the white
两者就都毁了
would be to ruin them both.
我喜欢桃红酒
I like a good rosé.
你好吗 不介意
Hey, how you doing? Would you mind...
我坐下吧
if I joined you?
要知道 甜品是一种享受
Dessert is an indulgence...
一个人独享的话就实在太蠢了
and I feel kinda silly and stupid indulging alone.
我一个人待着挺好的
I am at my happiest alone.
不过
But...
看在你这份丹麦卷的份上
for a small piece of your fragelité,
一起吧
please join me.
好的 不好意思 再拿把叉子
Oh, with pleasure. Excuse me, another fork?
我一直想找机会认识你 波洛先生
I've been trying to make your acquaintance, Mr. Poirot.
谢谢
Merci.
我从来没有这么近距离的接触过名人
I never ever sat so close to fame before.
不对
No, I tell a lie.
我曾和泰·柯布坐过一辆车
Once, I was on a bus with Ty Cobb.
底特律的球员
Ball player, Detroit. Ah.
你不介意我把顶上这些吃掉吧
Would you mind if I have the little curly bit at the top?
你还挺奇葩的
You're an odd bird there.
真是一个怪人
You're a strange, peculiar man.
到了这把年纪
I am of an age
我很清楚自己想要什么 不要什么
where I know what I like and what I do not like.
喜欢的东西尽情享受
What I like, I enjoy enormously.
不喜欢的绝不容忍
What I dislike, I cannot abide.
比如 谈生意前 人们都爱说的
For instance, the temporary pleasantries
那些客套话 我就很讨厌
before what is determined to be a business discussion.
你很有趣
You're fun.
好吧
All right.
我想雇你做一件事
I would like to offer you a job.
报纸上说
"The avenger of the innocent."
你是 还人清白的复仇者
It's what they call you in the papers.
你是清白的吗
And you are an innocent?
我是个商人
I'm a businessman.
买卖艺术品 虽然我入行不久
I'm an art dealer. I mean, I'm new to it.
不过新手总是运气不错
But my beginner's luck has panned out.
文物 古董
Relics, antiquities.
地毯 稀奇古怪的玩意儿 东方的一些东西
Rugs, weird. Orientals.
我还是个新手 所以眼光难免比较业余
I'm new to the game, so I got the amateur eyeball.
不过说实话 我有点看不惯那些
But I got a little problem with these, uh...
所谓的鉴定师
so-called appraisers.
全都不可靠
You can't trust a one of 'em.
我的一些客户
Some of my customers...
他们从我这买了东西
they buy a piece...
但后来发现 那些东西可能不是真品
they find out that they're not exactly original...
其实也不能怪我
which is hardly my fault...
我也不知道碦山丝巾会是假的
if a Kashan silk scarf is a fake.
对吧
Right? Huh?
没错
C'est bon.
但总之我有不少仇家
But I've managed to make a few enemies, is the thing.
我收到几封信 有人在威胁我
I got a few letters, people making threats.
我觉得最有嫌疑的是那帮意大利人
I think, most likely, it's the Italians.
我在米兰的时候 卖给他们一套东方地毯
I sold them a set of Oriental carpets in Milan.
然而 买家对货的来源不太满意
And the buyers weren't so happy with the provenance.
于是他们想把钱连本带利地要回去
And they want their money back with interest, you know?
意大利人
Italians.
就是这幅德行
A guinea's a guinea.
然后我眼前就出现了一位神探
And then comes along the genius detective.
你是说我吧
Me?
对 你 赫拉克勒斯·波洛
Yes, you. Hercules Poirot. Hercule.
不管怎样 我就直说吧
Here's what I'd like to do.
我想雇你保护我的安全
I would like to hire you to watch my back...
直到我去了安全的地方
until I get someplace safe.
这钱挺容易赚的
It's easy money for you.
我也能安心度过旅途
And it's peace of mind for me, you know?
- 明白了 - 那么?
I understand. Good.
我拒绝
I refuse.
什么? 这可不好
I'm sorry? That's bad.
可能我话没太说清楚
Maybe I didn't make myself clear enough.
你看 有人想要我的命
You see, someone's out to get me.
我知道我不是什么好人 甚至还差远了
And I know I'm not the best guy born, not by a long shot.
如果人死后真的有地狱
And if there's a world after this one,
到时候我会和你一样面对上帝的审判
I will face judgment just like you.
不过
But...
我可不想提前到那报道
I ain't in no goddamn rush to do it.
- 你是在拿枪指着我么 - 不
You're holding a gun on me? No.
不是对着你 是对着全世界
Not you. On the world.
- 我存在于这个世界 别对着我
I exist in the world. Do not point a gun at me.
一周给你10000块怎么样?
How's ten thousand sound for a week?
- 您很慷慨 雷切特先生 我拒绝
It's a generous offer, Mr. Ratchett. I must decline.
15000呢?
Fifteen thousand?
- 再说一遍 我拒绝
You didn't hear me. I decline.
明白了
Oh, I get it.
大侦探嫌这点钱不够
It's not flashy enough for the great Hercules Poirot, huh?
不光彩
No flashbulbs...
你把假冒文物卖给不法之徒
You sell fakes to gangsters.
你要自己承担后果
You're suffering the consequences.
我揪出恶人 不会保护他们
I detect criminals. I do not protect them.
所以你是觉得我的钱是脏钱咯
So you say "no" to my dirty money.
我只是拒绝你而已 雷切特先生
I say "no" to you, Mr. Ratchett.
因为这把枪的事吧 就因为这个?
Business with the gun, right? Is that what it was?
更多的是个人原因
It is far more personal than that.
我不喜欢你这张脸
I do not like your face.
请原谅 我要走了
If you will excuse me.
你喜欢我的蛋糕么
You liked my cake, didn't you?
挺不错的
The cake was excellent.
雷切特先生 祝您下午愉快
Have a pleasant afternoon, Mr. Ratchett.
谢谢
Thank you.
真冷啊
Ooh! Cold.
我亲爱的凯瑟琳
My sweet Katherine.
我的挚爱
My love.
狄更斯先生
Mr. Dickens.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
没什么事
It's nothing.
好的 先生
Very good sir.
晚安
Good night.
又怎么了
Mrs. Hubbard?
哈伯德夫人 还会有谁呢
It's always Mrs. Hubbard.
哈伯德夫人
Mrs. Hubbard.
我们死了吗
Did we die?
女士们先生们 我们的列车脱轨了
Ladies and gentlemen, the train has been derailed.
你还好吧 马奎兹先生
Are you all right, Mr. Marquez?
我没事 我没事 谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
请留在车厢里
You'll be safest in your cabins.
明天一早布克先生会和
Mr. Bouc will speak to you all...
大家说明情况
in the morning.
安全起见请留在包厢里
Please, you will be safest in your cabins.
当然
Of course.
我们会死么
Are we gonna die?
我的凯瑟琳
My Katherine.
我美丽的
My beautiful...
女士们 先生们 恐怕
Ladies and gentlemen, I am afraid
我们的列车暂时还不能重新启程
that our train is still unable to go anywhere.
一动就掉下去了
Yeah, except down.
我们还要在这儿等多久
How long are we supposed to just sit here?
是啊 总得有人做些什么吧
Yes, someone must be doing something.
我确实该做些什么 可我本人什么都不用做
Of course I am doing something. I am doing nothing.
准确来说两小时十分钟之前
Precisely two hours and ten minutes ago,
布罗德的站长见我们没能准时抵达
when we did not arrive in Brod as scheduled...
他一定已经猜到了我们的处境
the station master will have surmised our situation...
所以他会派人来扶正列车
and already dispatched a team to excavate the engine...
清理道路 好让我们继续前行
clear our path, and send us on our way.
在那之前 我保证
Until then, I assure you...
大家一定会享受到温暖而又舒适的列车服务
we will all be made warm and fed and comfortable.
我们可以走过去
We could walk.
走不了几步我们就会被冻死
We could die of exposure trying.
我之后还要赶去别的地方
I have a connection to make.
我的船后天从法国出发
My boat sails day after tomorrow from France.
我赌你赶不上了 我也到不了伦敦
Without you, I'd wager. Or me in London.
你得对我损失的时间负责 布克先生
I hold you accountable for my loss of time, Mr. Bouc.
女士 您不能把天气因素怪到我头上
Madam, you cannot hold me accountable for the weather.
谁让你是这儿管事的呢
Of course I can. You're the one here.
我在都灵的会议怎么办
And my conference in Turin?
我还得赶去索肖的汽车工厂呢
And I was to meet at the auto factory in Sochaux.
有些事冥冥中自有定数
Yes, some things, they are in God's hands.
我们能不能安全抵达目的地
It is not for us to say...
不由我们说了算
if we deserve to arrive safely at our destination...
又或者像邪恶天使路西法那样 我们注定坠落
or if, like Lucifer, we must fall.
您的早餐 雷切特先生
Breakfast for you, Mr. Ratchett.
早 马斯特曼先生
Ah, Bonjour, Mr. Masterman.
出什么事了吗
There is a problem?
我不知道 先生
I can't say, sir.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
不好意思
Excuse me.
里面有冷风
That is cold air.
请让布克先生赶紧过来
Please bring Monsieur Bouc immediately,
还有阿巴斯诺特医生
and also Dr. Arbuthnot.
我的天呐
Good God!
除了尸体 什么都别碰
Touch nothing else, only the body.
这太可怕了
My God, this is horrible.
先是大雪 现在又...
First the snow, now...
这下我必须得到
I'll have to meet with the police
站台和警察说明一下情况
and make some statement in some grimy station.
现在有人死在了这儿
And a man has died.
有人死在了这儿
是被捅死的
He was stabbed.
被一把长刀
Long, straight-edged knife.
有多处伤口 有的很浅
Multiple stab wounds, some shallow,
有的径直刺穿了肌肉
some cut clean through muscle.
左撇子还是右撇子
Left-hand side or right-hand side?
问题就在这儿
That's the thing.
凶手似乎是
It appears the killer
闭着眼睛在乱捅一气
maybe closed his eyes and struck blind.
你能不能推算一下死亡时间
Can you estimate the time of death?
说不准 里面窗户又开着
It's hard to say with the window open...
不过 我觉得应该是午夜到两点之间
but my best guess is between midnight and 2:00.
可没人进出过他的包厢
But no one went in his compartment then.
我整晚坐在外面
I sat in my seat all night.
有人进出我一定会看到 这不可能
I would have seen if someone went in. It's impossible.
谢谢你 医生 请回餐车去吧
Thank you, Doctor. Please, return to the dining car.
米歇尔 封锁他的包厢
Michel, secure this carriage.
波洛
Poirot.
你得帮我 朋友
I need your help, my friend.
你得找出凶手
You have to find who did this.
求你了 我代表东方快车公司
Please, I implore you,
恳求你
on behalf of the Orient Express.
等警察到了
When the police arrive,
我们可以直接告诉他们真相
we can present them with the case closed.
现在只有你才能救我
You are the only one who can save me.
你的信任让我非常感动
Your faith touches me, mon cher.
但我这次是来休假的
But I must have this rest.
你可以把它看作是海边的猜谜游戏
Well, think of it as a little beachside puzzle.
你根本就不用太费力气
That's nothing to your mind!
你只要看一眼乘客的出身背景
You look up the antecedents of the passengers.
看看他们有没有说谎
You establish their bona fides.
然后该干吗就干吗
Then you do what you do. You... You... You...
你可以坐在椅子里 然后 你边吃蛋糕边思考
You sit in a chair and you eat your cake...
直到真相浮出水面了
and you think until the solution presents itself.
不然在这冰天雪地里你还能干吗
What else are you going to do while we sit here in the snow?
没有东西刺激你的大脑
Without constant stimulation,
你的脑细胞会饿死的
your little gray cells will starve and die.
你以为就这么简单 坐在椅子里
You think that is what I do? I sit in a chair...
吃着小蛋糕
and I have a little piece of cake,
然后就破案了
and then I come up with a great idea?
我不知道你是怎么破案的 - 我还要读狄更斯
I don't know what you do. I have my Dickens.
去你的狄更斯
Damn your Dickens!
如果把案子交给警察
If we leave this to the police,
他们会随便找个替罪羊
they will choose a culprit...
无论他是不是真凶 那人都得死
right or wrong, and they will hang him.
很可能是马奎兹
Most probably Mr. Marquez...
不为什么 就因为他有个拉丁裔的名字
for no other reason than his name is Marquez.
或者那位医生 就因为他的肤色
Or Dr. Arbuthnot for the color of his skin.
现在只有你能主持公道
You are the only one who can bring justice.
给我一张车厢的图纸
Let me have a map of this coach.
好的
Of course.
所有人的护照 没问题
Every passport. Anything.
安排一下 我要询问每一名乘客
Interviews arranged with all of our passengers.
找出证据 记录下时间和顺序 揪出真凶
Evidence, order and method, until one culprit emerges.
我不能容忍谋杀行为 我的朋友
I do not approve of murder, my friend.
每天我们
Every day, we meet people
都会遇到一些败类
the world could do better without...
可我们不能杀死他们
yet we do not kill them.
我们应该有别于野兽
We must be better than the beasts.
就让我们找出这个凶手吧
So let us find this killer.
发生什么了
What's going on?
女士们先生们 有件事想告知大家
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to, um...
似乎我们的厄运不仅仅只是这场大雪
It appears that our bad luck has worsened.
很不幸
That is...
有一名乘客死在了车上
A passenger has died on the train.
雷切特先生
Monsieur Ratchett.
看来他们还是得逞了
Looks like they got him after all.
你觉得他是被谋杀的
You assume he was killed?
不 不
No, no.
我的意思是 他身体很健康
I just mean he was in perfectly good health.
不过却得罪了不少人
He had his enemies, that's all.
没错 他是被谋杀的
Indeed, he did. He was murdered.
天呐 谋杀 在这儿
Good God. Murder, here?
是的 女士
Alas, madame.
愿上帝保佑他安息
God rest his soul.
昨天半夜有人
Someone was rummaging around my cabin
闯进了我的包厢
in the middle of the night.
可没人相信我
Nobody would believe me.
到底怎么回事
What is going on?
既然我们哪儿都去不了
As we are snowbound,
布克先生已经
I have elected to take the case...
委托我调查此案并找出真凶
and find for my friend, Monsieur Bouc, the criminal.
为什么是你
And why you?
*我是赫尔克里·波洛
My name is Hercule Poirot...
可能是这个世上最伟大的侦探
and I am probably the greatest detective in the world.
我会单独找你们谈话
I will speak to all of you in time.
但现在
For the moment...
我建议你们
I must recommend that you remain
回到包厢把门锁上
in your compartments with the doors locked.
感觉像囚犯一样
I feel like a prisoner here.
这是为了你们自身的安全
It is for your own safety.
如果这是一起谋杀案
If there was a murder...
就一定会有凶手
then there was a murderer.
而他就在我们身边
The murderer is with us...
他在列车上 就现在
on the train, now.
车厢与车厢之间的门晚上都会上锁对吧
The doors between coaches were locked at night, hmm?
没错 我亲自锁的
Absolutely. Done myself.
已经搜过了
The train's been searched.
没人躲在车顶或者车底
There's no one hiding on it or under it.
这样我们就可以把范围
We can therefore limit our investigation
缩小到加来车厢的那几位乘客了
to the occupants of the Calais coach.
布克你来帮我
Bouc, you will assist me.
只有你睡在了别的车厢
As the only traveler who slept in another coach...
所以你是唯一没有嫌疑的人
you are the only one who is not a suspect.
麦奎因先生 您一定要现在喝酒吗
Mr. MacQueen, is this really the time for drinking?
我的老板死了
My boss is dead.
我丢了饭碗
I'm out of a job,
而你们像看犯人一样看着我
and you're looking at me like I did it.
我们并没有提出指控
We make no accusations.
你了解他 所以从你这儿
You knew him, so from here
我们能获得重要信息
we must glean the essential facts.
你们是亲戚吗
Were you his relative?
不 我是他秘书
No, his secretary.
帮他订票 替他点牛排
Book his travel, order his steaks.
他吃过的牛排
The man ate more steak
比我这辈子见过的还要多
than I've ever seen in my entire life.
他做古董生意
He was in antiques.
他没有文物方面的资历
He had no qualification for it,
没有眼光 也不会外语
not the eye or the languages.
不会记账
Truth is, he had no head for business, accounting...
这些都不懂
none of it.
全都是我在打理
I took care of everything.
你在他这儿工作多久了
How long were you in his employ?
差20天就满一年了
Twenty days shy of a year.
我受不了美国的禁酒令
Prohibition wasn't to my taste...
所以我 选择了去国外 还负了债
so I found myself overseas, and in debt.
我是学法律出身的
I'm a lawyer by education...
可惜我不是这块料
not disposition.
还搞得一团糟
I was downright awful at it.
你喜欢他的为人吗
You were fond of him?
我喜欢的是他的钱
I was fond of his money.
他为人粗俗
Ratchett was crude...
挑剔 爱骂人 很可能还犯过罪
demanding, insulting, and most likely a felon.
你最后见到他是什么时候
When did you last see him?
应该是刚过十点
It must have been just after 10:00.
他叫我过去核查一遍意大利的生意
He called me in to go over our sales in Italy.
在米兰卖出的那些赝品
Milan, the sale of forgeries?
对 没错
Yeah, yeah.
他想让我查看一下账目
He wanted to look over the accounts.
我得给他做翻译
I had to translate everything...
合同是法文写的
as the contracts were in French
他一个字都看不懂
and he didn't speak a word.
列车停靠在温科夫齐时
And when we stopped at Vinkovci...
我和黑人医生聊了会儿
I struck up a chat with the colored doctor, Arbuthnot.
我们还喝了几杯 活动一下腿脚
And we had a couple of drinks, stretched our legs.
我不太赞同
He had some...
他对斯大林的看法 所以想纠正他
odd opinions about Stalin I had to turn around.
我对那位医生没有种族偏见
I don't hold a man's race against him,
但我不怎么喜欢英国佬
but I don't often take to Britishers.
你们几点分开的
When did your party end?
他是在两点后走的
He left just after 2:00.
你知道雷切特的仇家
Did you know of any specific enemies
具体有谁吗
Ratchett might have had?
天呐
Gosh.
多了去了
Pick a number.
他说有人威胁他是吧
He confided he had been threatened?
他收到了几封恐吓信
He got a couple of nasty letters.
我这里正好有几封 要看吗
I have them if you like. Some, anyway.
其它的都被他撕了
He tore up the rest.
一把火烧了
Threw them into the fire.
就这些
That's them.
谢谢你 麦奎因先生
Merci, Mr. MacQueen.
谢谢
Uh, thank you.
如果还有别的问题
If we have any further questions,
我们会再来找你的
we will call for you again.
你们怀疑过那个拉丁人
Have you considered the Latin man?
马奎兹吗 那家伙挺可疑的
Marquez. Hell of a guy.
而且你们也知道
And, well, you know, his kind...
拉丁人并不反感杀人
they don't have the same distaste for murder,
历史经验是这样的
historically speaking.
你不是说你没有种族偏见吗
You said you don't hold a man's race against him.
或许
I suppose...
得看是哪个种族
depends on the race.
他本来表现得还不错
And he was doing so well.
你觉得是他?  现在还太早
You think it's MacQueen? Too early to say.
很难想象他会有底气
I admit, I cannot see him
朝一个人连捅12刀
stabbing a man twelve times in a frenzy.
可能是酒精作祟  不然还会是谁
Not sober, anyway. Who did it then?
我还不知道 得问一个人
I do not know yet. It is time we ask.
去问谁 - 受害者的尸体
Ask who? The victim.
受害者被捅了12刀
He has twelve stab wounds
正如医生所说伤口深浅不一
and, as Arbuthnot said, they are patternless.
如果是医生干的
If the doctor is guilty...
至少在这点上
he certainly did not let it influence
并没有说假话
his responsibilities.
看这儿 停在了一点15
Hey, the watch. Stopped at 1:15.
和死亡时间一致
Now that agrees with the doctor on the time of death.
有可能 确实有可能
Hmm. It is possible, yes. Certainly possible.
我不明白
I don't quite understand.
我自己也不明白
I do not understand, myself.
至今毫无头绪
I understand nothing at all.
如果你看这两道伤口
If you look at these two wounds...
看得出来力道很大 插得很深 但流血很少
they are powerful and deep, and yet there is little blood.
可这明明是一次疯狂的袭击
But this was a frenzied attack.
凶手连续捅了很多刀
Lashing here and there.
用力不均但却极端暴力
No pattern at all, just extreme violence.
而我们的死者
And during all this, our victim,
为人暴躁又焦虑 还喝了那么多咖啡
vigorous and anxious and full of coffee...
却在这一过程静静的躺在这儿 丝毫没有反抗
merely lies still and accepts death without struggle...
而与此同时
when he also has here...
他的枕头下面还准备了防身用的武器
the means by which he might defend himself.
给你拿着
For you.
再来看看这个
Now, let us see here.
巴比妥 服用了会让人昏睡
Barbital. The Mickey slipped.
这样他就没法用手枪了
Drugged him so he couldn't use this.
同时这儿还有一条女士手帕
And later around here, a lady's handkerchief.
十分贵重 手工制作
An objet de luxe, handmade.
在巴黎要卖200法郎
Boom, two hundred francs in Paris.
上面还绣了一个大写字母“H"
And she even has an initial, "H."
还有这玩意儿
And our little friend,
清烟斗的通条 又一个线索
the pipe cleaner. Another clue.
对 犯人留下了那么多显而易见的线索
Yes, a riot of clues dropped most conveniently.
但或许事实上只有一个才是真的
Yet only one appears, however, to be perhaps genuine.
烟灰缸里
And maybe this ashtray provides
不经意地留下的蛛丝马迹
the accidental breadcrumb.
一张烧焦的字条
A charred fragment of a note.
也可能是凶手试图毁灭的证据
An attempt, perhaps, to burn evidence.
谢谢先生
Merci, monsieur.
我们可以借用一下工具吧
We may borrow your equipment, yes?
谢了
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Merci, merci.
相比现场留下了什么证物
Now, I prefer to understand...
我更好奇为什么会把它们留在案发现场
why a clue is left rather than what the object is.
要从事物发内部探寻真相 而不是看表象
We seek the truth from within, not without.
所以现在
In this case, however,
我们可能需要借助一下科学的力量
I may welcome a little scientific assistance.
你来帮我控制火焰
You will adjust the flame.
又是一封恐吓信
It's just another one of those nasty letters.
你错了 我的朋友
You are mistaken, mon ami.
这些文字另有玄机
This one has a secret to tell.
看
Look.
你的手上沾着斯特朗的血 你会丧命
"As a strong blood is on hand, you will die."
什么意思
What does this mean?
跟我来 布克
Come with me, Bouc.
我们把缺失的部分补上
Let us fill in the gaps.
这不再是海边的猜谜游戏了
This was never a beachside puzzle.
我知道死者的真正身份了
I know the dead man's real name.
他不叫雷切特 而叫卡萨蒂
It is not Ratchett, but Cassetti.
我听过这名字
I know that name.
那你一定也听过阿姆斯特朗这名字
Then you will also know the name Armstrong.
你是说阿姆斯特朗惨案
The Armstrong case?
那起案子震惊了全世界
The story shocked the world.
两年前
Two years ago...
著名飞行员 约翰·阿姆斯特朗上校
the renowned pilot, Colonel John Armstrong...
和妻子索尼娅
and his wife, Sonia,
醒来后发现他们的独生女小黛西
woke to find their only child, little Daisy...
在睡梦中遭人绑架
taken from her crib as she slept.
走投无路的
Desperate...
阿姆斯特朗夫妇支付了赎金
the Armstrongs paid the ransom.
但不久后 人们还是找到了黛西的尸体
But soon after, Daisy was found murdered by...
凶手就是雷切特 也就是卡萨蒂
Ratchett, who was Cassetti.
得知这一噩耗时
Sonia Armstrong was with child
索尼娅已经怀有身孕
when she received the news.
这一刺激导致婴儿早产
The shock sent her into premature labor.
母子二人都没能活下来
Neither she nor her baby survived.
你怎么知道的 波洛
How do you know this, Poirot?
因为是约翰·阿姆斯特朗告诉我的
Because John Armstrong told me so himself.
他写信给我请求帮助
He wrote to me to ask me for my help.
当我收到那封信时
By the time I received his letter...
已经太迟了
it was too late.
人们发现他中枪而亡
He was found dead of a gunshot wound.
是自杀
Self-inflicted.
你手上沾着黛西·阿姆斯特朗的血
"Daisy Armstrong's blood is on your hands.
你会为此丧命
"You will die for it."
到头来的确如此
Indeed, you did.
波洛先生 怎么了 米歇尔
Monsieur Poirot? Yes, Michel.
哈伯德夫人有话和你说
Mrs. Hubbard wants to speak to you.
我已经尽量拖住她了
I held her as best as I could.
哈伯德夫人 抱歉 久等了
Ah, Mrs. Hubbard, I'm sorry to have kept you.
听说你有一肚子的火和一肚子的话要说
You have a head full of steam and a mouth full of words.
没错 算你说对了 这些话我今天
You're goddamn right, I do. What I have been trying...
一早就想对你说了
to tell you all day.
你们要找的那名凶手 昨晚去过我的包厢
The murderer was in my compartment last night.
我以为他会杀了我 的确有人丧命
I thought I'd be killed. Turns out I might have been...
只不过死的却是雷切特
only he got Ratchett instead.
我在黑暗中惊醒
I woke up in the dark, and I knew
发现包厢里有个男人
there was a man in my room.
你确定那是一个男人
You are certain it was a man?
我知道有男人在我房间的感觉是什么样的
I know what it feels like to have a man in my bedroom.
我告诉了列车员 可他却不相信我
I told your conductor, and he wouldn't believe me.
我说检查下
I said, "Check the communication door
我和雷切特包厢之间的连接门
"between my room and Ratchett's.
凶手肯定从那儿跑了
"He must have left through there."
不出所料 门并没有上锁
Sure enough, it was unbolted.
我特意锁好的
I know I locked it...
因为雷切特说了那些话
after what Ratchett said.
他提了一些颇为露骨的要求
He made a rather overt overture.
你之前有没有听说过
Have you perhaps...
阿姆斯特朗绑架案
heard of the Armstrong kidnapping?
这么骇人听闻
You couldn't avoid it.
想不知道都难
Morbid stuff.
杀害那孩子的凶手 卡萨蒂
The child's murderer, Cassetti...
昨晚死了
died last night.
就是雷切特
Ratchett was the man.
我早就说过 我一看就知道他有问题
I told you, I knew he was a rotten one.
你相信我吗
You do believe me...
我房里确实有人
about the man in my room?
我知道你觉得我是个蠢女人
I'm aware you think I'm a silly woman.
可是我有证据 是真的
But I have proof it's true.
这是东方快车
It is from the uniform...
列车员制服上的
of an Orient Express conductor...
可能是米歇尔
but it might have fallen from Michel's
在你房间时落下的
when he was in your room.
我的扣子没掉
I'm not missing any.
我是在
I found it
床尾的被子上找到的
at the foot of my bed, on the cover...
就在我睡觉的地方
right where I slept.
你怎么看
What do you call that?
的确是有力证据 非常感谢哈伯德夫人
I call it evidence. Thank you so much, Mrs. Hubbard.
你去过美国吗
Have you ever been to America?
去过一次
Once.
几年前 呆了没几天
Years ago, briefly.
去那儿干嘛
For what purpose?
去验证一个猜想 什么猜想
To confirm a suspicion. Which was?
我猜我不喜欢美国
That I wouldn't like it.
波士顿那边有个工作机会
I was offered a post in Boston.
但一到那儿我就直接回伦敦了
Saw Boston, went straight back to London.
雷切特不就是那儿的人吗
Is that where Ratchett was from?
波士顿 我并不知道这些
Boston? I can't says I know.
一般不太会问别人
It wouldn't be proper...
这种问题
to ask.
请继续
Carry on.
我最后见到
I last saw...
雷切特先生应该是九点
Mr. Ratchett at nine o'clock.
我去送咖啡  把他的衣服挂好了
I brought his coffee and hung up his clothes.
我猜你牙疼犯了吧
You have a toothache, I think.
我预约了这周回伦敦拔牙
I've got an extraction booked in London this week.
雷切特先生叮嘱我说这事不能再拖了
Mr. Ratchett insisted on not putting it off any longer.
他说他受不了
He said he was tired of hearing
我哼哼唧唧的声音
my suppressed groans.
这么有同情心的雷切特先生
This sympathetic Ratchett...
平时晚上都会喝咖啡吗
was it his usual practice to drink coffee at night?
以前不会 不过他最近有点焦虑
Not at all. But he'd been very agitated lately.
总说要让自己保持警惕
Said he wanted to stay alert, especially so last night.
尤其是昨晚他在包厢里发现了一封信
He found a letter in his compartment.
这应该不是你做的吧
Please tell me you didn't do this.
如果是我做的话
If I were to leave something unpleasant
恐怕就不只是
on your pillow, sir...
留张纸条那么简单了
it would not be a letter.
咖啡
Coffee.
一名
Surely, such a...
称职 细心的男仆
proper and precise valet...
是绝不会那样和主人说话的
would never speak to his master as you did?
除非他知道 自己这份工作
Unless he knew his career was coming to a sudden...
很快就会结束
end.
我猜你不仅仅是牙疼吧
No mere toothache, I think.
肺癌
The lungs?
是甲状腺
The thyroid.
已经转移到了胃
Spread now to stomach.
和我父亲一样 他死时比我还年轻五岁
Same as got my father, five years younger.
最多再活几个月
Months at best.
医生说恐怕手术无法治愈
"Inoperable, I'm afraid," said the doctor.
突然间我再也不怕了
And suddenly, I wasn't... afraid.
现在我只想做一些想做的事
I would only do what I wanted from here on.
说自己想说的话
I speak my mind now.
那杯咖啡
The coffee.
有人肯定朝里面下了镇定剂
It appears that his cup was laced with barbital.
你肯定会说
You, of course, will tell me
那不是你干的
that you did not put it in there.
当然不是我
Of course I didn't.
你什么时候
When and from where
从哪里拿的杯子和咖啡
did you procure the coffee and the cups?
就在厨房拿的
In the kitchen, sir.
我晚餐时点的 说好九点去拿 就是那样
I ordered it at dinner to be ready at 9:00, and so it was.
在我之前谁都可能接触到那杯咖啡
Anybody could have got a hold of it before me.
谢谢
Merci.
马斯特曼先生
Mr. Masterman.
牙疼的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about the toothache.
谢谢
Merci.
我喜欢那些小蛋糕
I love the little cakes.
皮拉尔·艾斯特拉瓦多斯小姐
So, Miss Pilar Estravados, you are a missionary...
你是名传教士
but you trained as a nurse
但在改行前你曾经做过保姆对吧
before you changed professions, yes?
是我欠上帝的
I owed it to God.
为什么说是欠上帝的
You owed Him a debt?
我曾经
There were...
有过一段非常放纵的生活
indulgent times in my life...
当时的我 索取的太多 给予的太少
when I took more than I gave.
格哈德哈德曼
Gerhard Hardman.
工程学教授
Professor of engineering.
正是因为科学
It is science that will win back
德国才有幸找回了她昔日的光辉
for Germany her pride.
贝尼亚米诺·马奎兹 - 马奎兹先生
- Biniamino Marquez. - Mr. Marquez.
听着 我不想和
Listen, I wanna be clear
这起案子扯上任何关系
of any association with the crime...
有问题尽管问我
so please ask me anything.
随便问 我绝不隐瞒
Anything. I never lie anymore.
你昨天有离开过包厢吗
Did you leave your compartment at all last night?
就离开过一次 去要阿司匹林
Only once, to get an aspirin.
哈伯德夫人早先就说过要给我药
Mrs. Hubbard offered me something earlier.
起初我拒绝了 可我实在睡不好
I declined at first, but when I couldn't rest...
就去找她要了点药
I went to ask for it.
我的会议将在都灵举行
My conference is in Turin.
会议上只有我一个奥地利人
I am the only Austrian to present,
所以如果我没到场
which means without me...
会议将延期
the talks will be substandard.
于是我逃出了监狱
Then I escaped prison,
搞了个美国身份
and I bribed myself into the US...
从此发誓再也不干偷鸡摸狗的事
where I swore never to lie or steal again.
因为当人们信任你时
You see, my friends, because when people
会向你买更多东西
trust you, they buy more.
意大利人就是奶牛 西班牙人就像绵羊
The Italians are cows. The Spaniards, sheep.
比利时人吗
The Belgians...
当时没发现什么 我回到房间
I come to my room, which I share
同屋住的是那个英国管家
with the unhappy English butler.
像鱼一样 因为总是在嘟哝着什么
A fish. He groans a lot.
但他可以证明我一觉睡到大天亮
But I'm sure he saw me sleep all night until morning.
有件事情
I should say...
我想应该和案情有关
in case it is relevant...
当我去找哈伯德夫人的时候
there was an embarrassing moment.
发生了尴尬的一幕
When I went to see Mrs. Hubbard...
一开始我走错房间了
first, I opened the wrong door.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
当时是几点
What time was this?
应该差不多是
That must have been about...
不用道歉
Don't be sorry.
晚上十点四十
...twenty minutes to 11:00.
有意思
This is interesting.
到现在为止
As far as it is known,
你应该是最后一个见到他活着的人
you are the last person to see Ratchett alive.
你是个商人 卖汽车的
Your business? Automobiles.
我有三个展厅
I have three showrooms.
当年我到美国时一穷二白 现在呢
I come to America with nothing. And now...
我会去向德贝汉小姐求证
If what you say is true,
你所说的话
Miss Debenham will confirm it.
我说的全是真的
But it is true.
我不会说谎
I would not lie.
或许德贝汉小姐
May it be possible that Miss Debenham
离开过你们的包厢 而你没有察觉到
left your compartment without you noticing?
不 我睡得很浅
No. I sleep very lightly.
稍稍有点动静 我马上就会惊醒
The slightest sound and I bolt upright.
我曾经遇到过意外
I was surprised once.
不会再有第二次
Never again.
不 我没说我当过专职司机
No, I didn't say I was a chauffeur.
你的行李箱掉下来时 照片撒了一地
The photographs that spilled out of your luggage...
里面有一张漂亮的照片
there was a beautiful one
一个小男孩戴着司机的帽子
with a little boy wearing a chauffeur's hat...
估计是来找正在上班的爸爸
visiting his papa at work.
你给谁当的司机
Who did you chauffeur?
女士 你手上的老茧很多
Miss Estravados, why do your hands
就像拳击手一样
have the calluses of a boxer?
我工作的城市大都非常危险
I do my work in dangerous cities...
为了让自己不生活在恐惧当中
where I cannot be governed by fear.
我接受过搏击训练
I trained to fight.
经历那次意外之后
But you do not trust your god anymore...
你连上帝也不信了?
since your surprise?
不 以防他忙不过来
No, in case He is busy.
上帝一直都很忙
God is always busy.
是马斯特曼
It's Masterman.
一个将死之人没什么可顾忌的了
A man dying is a man with nothing to lose.
很好 布克 但有个问题
Bravo, Bouc. Except for the problem of Mr. Marquez...
马奎兹先生已经证实了
who has now confirmed
他的室友马斯特曼先生在案发当时
that his bunkmate, Masterman...
正在床上看书
was reading in his bed at the time of death.
真这么简单我就不会出名了 下一个
If it were easy, I would not be famous. Next.
德贝汉小姐
Miss Debenham...
你不介意出来透透气吧
you do not mind to brace the air?
为你 我们准备了野餐
For you, we have the picnic.
询问我室友时选在了狭隘的地方
While you made my roommate suffer cramped quarters.
我懂了
I see.
不同对象
Choose the best location
选择在不同地点询问他们
to extract the truth from each suspect.
让她措不及防 让我来受冻
Put her off-balance and me, freeze.
你很聪明
Clever.
请写下你的全名和
Will you write down your full name
地址好吗
and address, please?
对了 是淡紫色
A pale mauve, by the way.
艾斯特拉瓦多斯小姐说你问了
Miss Estravados told me you asked
她睡袍的颜色
the color of her dressing gown.
谢谢
Merci.
玛丽·赫尔迈厄尼·德贝汉
"Mary Hermione Debenham."
有人会叫你赫尔迈厄尼吗
Do you ever go by Hermione?
除了工作时大家都叫我玛丽
A constant Mary, when I'm not employed as Miss Debenham.
左撇子
Left-handed.
很罕见 我知道
Unusual, I know.
你还在研究笔迹
You mustn't have your theory fixed
那就证明你还没有结论
if you're testing my handwriting.
你怎么看死者
What did you think of the dead man?
我基本上没怎么注意他
Uh, I can't say I did think about him.
我不懂这个问题的意义何在
I don't quite see the point of your question.
原谅我 小姐 这是我的一个小诀窍
Oh, forgive me, mademoiselle, my little originalities.
人性多变而且复杂
Human nature is perverse in its complexity.
所以想要抽丝剥茧 就得用对工具
To plumb it, it takes the right tools.
你这是把戏不是工具 赫尔克里
These are toys, not tools, Hercule.
我希望你更直接些
I prefer you put them away.
更直接吗 很好
The direct method? Parfait.
你和医生之前就认识吧
You knew the doctor before traveling?
阿巴斯诺特医生
Dr. Arbuthnot?
不
No.
所以是一见钟情
But such instant attraction?
这里不是美国
We are not in America...
德贝汉小姐 这里没有法律
Miss Debenham. There are no laws
会制约你的感情
against what you may feel.
同时也没有哪条法律不允许我缄默
Nor are there laws against silence, of which...
所以我
I hold my...
我从没去过美国
I've never been to America.
我还想问你 关于我无意中
Perhaps I may ask about some...
听到的几句话
words I overheard?
你和阿巴斯诺特似乎
You and the stranger, Arbuthnot,
要比一般陌生人来得更亲近些
are closer than strangers might be.
我听你说
You said...
不是现在 事成之后 就没人能阻碍我们了
"Not now. When we are done. Then no one can touch us."
什么意思
What did you mean?
你以为我说的谋杀?
You think I meant murder?
拿着锤子的人眼里到处都是钉子
To a man with a hammer, every problem is a nail.
你看多了罪犯
You live crime.
就觉得所有人都是魔鬼 - 正相反
You see evil every day. Not so.
我看多了罪犯
I see enough crime to know
所以我知道哪些地方不寻常
that the criminal act is the anomaly.
我相信一个人如果杀了另一个人
I believe it takes a fracture of the soul...
他的灵魂就不会再完整
to murder another human being.
我再问一遍 那话到底什么意思
I ask again, what did you mean?
正如我刚才说的
As we established...
没有哪条法律要求我一定要开口
there are no laws against my silence.
那好吧
Very well.
接下来是德拉戈米罗夫公主
And afterwards, Princess Dragomiroff?
吃完晚餐 我就去睡了
After dinner, I came to bed.
上帝让我长寿
God blessed me with long life,
但却让我受到背痛的困扰 让我痛苦不已
but cursed me with a bad back to make it miserable.
大概是十二点三刻
About a quarter to 1:00...
我叫来了施密特小姐
I called for Fräulein Schmidt.
让她给我做按摩
Mmm-hmm. She massaged me...
给我念了会书
and read to me for a while.
之后我就睡着了
- Then I sleep. - Mmm-hmm.
您认不认识
Were you ever acquainted...
阿姆斯特朗一家人
with a family by the name of Armstrong?
他们遭遇了惨绝人寰的悲剧
They endured an unspeakable tragedy.
我很欣赏索尼娅·阿姆斯特朗的母亲
I was an admirer of Sonia Armstrong's mother...
琳达·雅顿  她是个演员
Linda Arden, the actress.
百年一遇的奇才
A once-a-century talent.
雅顿小姐当时想转做导演
Miss Arden was to turn to directing.
要不是那场悲剧
She would have become the first
我想她早就成为了
woman titan of Broadway...
百老汇第一位女巨人
were it not for the tragedy.
那么这位琳达·雅顿死了吗
And this Linda Arden, she is dead?
还不如死了呢
She might as well be.
从此以后 她足不出户
She no longer leaves her home.
黛西 是我的教女
Daisy was my goddaughter.
她是个
She was a...
我不明白这和这起案子有什么关系
I don't see how this relates to our troubles, Detective.
昨晚的受害人 他的真名叫做卡萨蒂
The man killed last night, his true name was Cassetti.
杀死小黛西·阿姆斯特朗的凶手
The man who murdered little Daisy Armstrong.
我懂了
I see.
我确实认识这家人 现在那家伙却死了
I admit I know this family, and now this man is dead.
这么巧合
The coincidence...
实在说不过去
must seem unbearable.
或许 这确实只是个巧合
You may be permitted a coincidence.
不过现在 我有一些问题要问这位施密特小姐
I must now ask a few questions of your Fräulein Schmidt.
不 没这个必要
No. There is no need.
我可以为她的人格作担保
I can answer to her character.
既然如此 如果您允许的话
Even still, if you will allow.
小姐 请用德语回答
Fraulein. Answer please in German.
这样公主殿下就听不懂我说的了
But her Excellency cannot comprehend me.
目的就是这个
That is the point.
这是你的吗  H指的是你的名字希尔德加德
This is yours? H for Hildegarde?
我用不起这么高级的东西
It is too fine for me.
关于昨晚的事  她说的是实话吗
This is the truth about last night?
正如她所说的 她让列车员把我叫来
As she said. She sent the conductor for me,
然后我就回去睡觉了
then I returned to bed.
你回去的时候有看到谁吗
Did you see anyone when you returned?
只看到了另一名列车员
Only the other conductor.
另一名列车员
"The other conductor."
是指米歇尔吗
You mean Michel?
不 不是那个叫醒我的人
No. A different one than had awoken me.
请跟我来
Please come with me.
你确定不是他吗
Are you sure you did not see him?
我确定 另一个
I'm certain. The other conductor
身材矮小 留着短胡子
was a small man with a short beard.
小姐 这儿只有一名列车员
Fräulein, there is no other conductor.
我看的很清楚
I know what I saw.
我记得他的声音很尖
I remember because his voice was high
穿着同样的制服
and the uniform was the same exactly.
我猜上面还少了一颗纽扣
Though, I suspect, missing one button.
现在我急需你的总钥匙
Sir, I need your passkey immediately.
我们要找一件制服和一件红色的和式睡袍
We need to find a uniform and a red kimono.
只找到几千张照片
Thousands of photographs,
无数双袜子
endless pairs of socks...
五颜六色的睡袍 就是没有红色的
dressing gowns in every color but red...
也没找到列车员的制服
and still no contraband conductor's uniform.
所有乘客的行李箱都查过了吗
Have we checked all the passengers' luggage?
除了安德烈伯爵
All except for the Count
和他夫人的行李还没查
and Countess Andrenyi, monsieur.
我们无权搜查他们的行李箱
It is forbidden to search their suitcases.
他们持有外交签证
They travel under diplomatic visas.
那还会去哪儿呢
Where else could it be?
还有一个人的行李箱没有查过
There is one last suitcase we have not checked.
我自己的
My own.
凶手是在嘲笑我
The killer is mocking me.
很好 这是他犯的第一个错误
Good. His first mistake.
那么有些事我自然也猜到了
And as the night must follow the day...
抱歉小姐
Pardon, mademoiselle.
不 这不是我的
No, it's not mine.
如果真是我的
I told you of the conductor. Why would I tell you
我为什么要告诉你呢
if it was me? You would not...
确实如此 所以你的包厢是最安全的地方
which makes your compartment the ideal choice to hide it.
少了颗纽扣
Voilà, the button.
如果这个人能够找到列车员的制服
And if a conductor's uniform...
他又怎么可能找不到列车员的钥匙呢
why not a conductor's passkey?
现在我们知道凶手
Now we know how the killer
是如何打开上了锁的门了
magically passed through locked doors.
波旁酒的味道 - 麦奎因
Bourbon. MacQueen.
要找什么
Now what are we looking for now?
500英镑
500 pounds.
麦奎因也有个账本
MacQueen also had a ledger.
记录了他和雷切特的所有生意
All his dealings with Ratchett.
在哪
Where is it, hmm?
波洛
Poirot?
布克 让大家都别出来
Bouc, keep everyone inside!
先生 请站住
Monsieur! Please stop!
先生
Monsieur!
请站着别动
Please stay where you are.
谢谢 先生们 多谢
Thank you, gentlemen. Thank you.
所以 是麦奎因干的 凶手抓到了
So, it was MacQueen? You have your man?
不好意思 女士
Pardonnez-moi, madame.
怎么会是他
How could he?
我没杀他
I didn't kill him!
你企图烧掉账本
You tried to burn Ratchett's accounts...
可有些地方还是看得出来
but they are still legible in places.
数字根本对不上
The maths do not tally...
因为你偷了他的钱
because you have been stealing from him.
这简直就是
It is full of the...
-  英语里面要怎么说 - 就是指很混乱
- What is the English word? - The chocolat?
糊涂账
Fudge? Fudge!
一笔糊涂账
It is full of the fudge!
你偷了他的钱
You stole from him!
你怕他会发现
You thought you would be found out.
所以你就杀了他
That is why you killed him!
对
Yeah.
你说得对 我是偷了他的钱
Yeah, you're damn right I stole from him.
好几千块
Thousands.
我知道他的钱不干净
I knew his money wasn't honest.
既然这样我揩点油又有什么关系
What did it matter if I skimmed some off the top?
我倒想问你一个问题
But let me ask you a question.
我为什么要做杀鸡取卵的事情
Why would I slaughter my cash cow?
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
- 我没杀他 - 不是他
- I didn't kill him! - He didn't.
不是他
He didn't.
我可以做他的不在场证明
I expect his alibi revolves around me,
我们凌晨时在喝酒
drinking till the early hours.
是真的
Well, it's true.
我看他在喝威士忌
I saw him having whiskey, and remarked
然后就说美国酒不如英国的好
on the lesser quality of American liquor.
他想让我改观
He offered me a tipple
就请我喝了几杯
to change my mind, then another.
我们当时探讨了政治话题
We got to arguing politics. He had some...
我不太赞同他对斯大林的一些看法
tomfool opinions on Stalin
但对于酒他确实很在行
I had to correct. But the man knows his spirits.
借一步说话 先生
A word, please, monsieur.
你确定你们整晚都在一起吗
You can confirm you were with him all night?
我们抽烟聊天到将近两点
We smoked and spoke till nearly 2:00, yes.
你们俩还真是投缘 他抽的是烟
Ah, such chums, him with his cigarettes, and you...
我记得你是这车上唯一抽烟斗的人
Yes, you are the only man on the train who smokes a pipe.
能看一下你的烟斗和烟丝吗
May I see your pipe and your tobacco, please?
当然
Of course.
阿巴斯诺特医生
And you, Dr. Arbuthnot,
你是从印度出发的对吧
were traveling from India, I believe. Yes?
现在开始审问我了吧
You're interviewing me now? Mmm-hmm.
在雷切特被杀前你去过他的包厢吗
Were you ever in Ratchett's compartment
当然没有
before he was killed? Certainly not.
这可是你的烟斗通条不是吗
But this is one of your pipe cleaners, n'est-ce pas?
如果是在死者的包厢里找到的 劝你再找仔细点
If you found that in the dead man's cabin, look elsewhere.
我是名医生
I am a doctor, sir.
我只会救人不会害人
I heal people. I do not hurt them.
说到这点 你一定非常努力
About this, see, you must have worked
才能当上医生
very hard to become a doctor.
很少有非洲裔的朋友有机会当上医生
Not many of your race are allowed the opportunity.
米德尔塞克斯医学院每个班只招一个黑人
Middlesex Medical College permits one per class.
我1924年入的学
I had the honor in '24.
我服役时是一名狙击手
I was a sniper in my tour.
射的很准
A sharpshooter.
我救了不少军官
Saved more than a few officers.
其中有人心存感激
The more grateful,
赏识我头脑冷静 双手稳健
recognized a fair mind with a steady hand...
资助我完成了学业
and supported my education.
我从此欠下了人情
I take their generosity as a debt.
认识阿姆斯特朗上校吗
Did you know a Colonel Armstrong?
有两三个姓阿姆斯特朗的
Might have known two or three Armstrongs.
第60步兵团有个汤米·阿姆斯特朗
Tommy in the 60th... Selby Armstrong...
不 我说的是约翰·阿姆斯特朗
No, I meant Colonel John Armstrong.
他娶了个美国妻子
He had an American wife,
而他的孩子被绑匪撕票了
and his child was kidnapped and killed.
我不认识他
Never came across the fellow.
第一次见德贝汉小姐是什么时候
When did you first meet Miss Debenham?
我们第一次见面是在护卫车上
We met when we shared the railway convoy car
从基尔库克到尼西宾
from Kirkuk to Nissibin.
她可不是这么说的
She claims otherwise,
这点让她变得非常可疑
and she has made herself problematically suspicious.
抱歉 失陪了
Excusez-moi.
玛丽是个好人
Mary is a lady.
别把她扯进来 我可以为她的人格担保
Leave her out of this. I can vouch for her character.
就像你担保麦奎因的不在场证明一样吗
As you vouched for MacQueen's time?
你根本不听别人说什么 没错
You won't listen to reason. Never.
算你走运 好心的医生说
You are lucky. The good doctor insists
他一直跟你在一起
he did not let you out of his sight.
看吧 所以不可能是我
See? There. Couldn't have done it.
当然有可能
Yes, you could.
雷切特每晚都会服用安眠药
Ratchett took a sleeping draught each evening.
你可以轻易的混入镇定剂
You could add barbital, easily access that drug.
再给医生的酒杯里也放点
Do the same with one of the doctor's many drinks...
这样你就有机会杀人了
and the chance to kill him is clear.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do any of that?
动机刚才已经分析过了
We have established your motive.
或许还有别的动机
Perhaps I will suggest a different one.
还有内情 可能是出于更私人的原因
A different reason, a more personal reason.
学法律出身 可惜却不是这块料
"A lawyer by education, not by disposition."
我很好奇你为什么学法律
Why did you pursue the law, I wonder?
是不是为了应付
Was it to appease a much loved,
你敬爱而又严厉的父亲
but demanding father...
他曾经是那么的成功
one who himself had made a great success
同样是在法律界
in the same field...
不过后来 他失势了
and then lost his position?
曾经有一个大名鼎鼎的麦奎因 不是吗
There was a renowned MacQueen, was there not?
他是新泽西州的一名地方检察官
The district attorney for the state of New Jersey...
也就是当年
responsible for the prosecution
阿姆斯特朗案的公诉人
of the Armstrong case.
他们找不到嫌疑犯
They didn't have a suspect.
我爸爸被迫将矛头指向了
My dad was pressured to go after
那个可怜的法国女人
this poor French woman...
那个女佣没有有力的不在场证明 苏珊
a maid with a weak alibi, Susanne.
他把罪责归咎于她
He hung his whole case on her.
然后她自杀了
She killed herself.
她是无辜的
She was innocent.
后来有证据显示凶手是卡萨蒂
By the time the evidence lead to Cassetti,
可他早跑了
oh, he was long gone.
我父亲成了众矢之的
They tore my old man apart.
可我却帮不了他
I couldn't do anything for him.
即便是这样
And yet you claim
你还说不知道雷切特就是卡萨蒂
that you did not know Ratchett was Cassetti?
不  不
No, no.
可你还是找到了他
But you found him.
不
No.
你找到了他
You found him.
卷走了他的钱
You bled him dry... No.
好还清你父亲欠下的债
in order to settle your father's debts,
于是到了最后 替你父亲报了仇
and then finally, to settle the score.
我没有
No, no, no.
不是这样的
No. It wasn't...
我只不过是
It wasn't like that. It's not the way...
有人闯了进来
Someone kicked in the door...
医生
Doctor!
捂住了我的脸
covered my face.
先得把刀拔出来
All right, this needs to come out now.
拿我的包来  好的
I want my bag. Of course.
在我的包厢里
It's in my compartment.
上面不会有指纹
There will be no fingerprints.
凶手想把凶器处理掉
The killer was disposing of the murder weapon.
就在那儿
It's there!
幸好没伤到肺和动脉
The killer didn't hit a lung or artery.
能活着算走运了
She's lucky to be alive.
你们都很走运
You all are.
我们的大侦探
Yeah, some genius!
你为什么还没有破案
Why haven't you solved this case?
你得给他一点时间
You must give the man some time.
行了
Yeah, well...
再给他时间我的血都要流干了
I can't give that much more. I don't have any blood left.
拉着麦奎因谈话
Accosting Mr. MacQueen,
结果真凶却在这儿
and the real killer is right here.
你们中的一个
One of you people.
我不知道那人是谁 我什么也没说
I don't know who you are. I said nothing.
求你 放过我吧
Please, leave me alone.
放点音乐
Play something.
各位 铁轨明早就能清理好
My friends, the tracks will be cleared by morning.
请回房休息吧
Please, return to your rooms.
我就睡在这儿
I'm sleeping here...
你们都看得到我 我也看得到你们
where everyone can see me and I can see everyone.
你们都该如此
You should all do the same. Conserve heat.
明早之前最好待在明处 彼此有个照应
Remain in the open, safely in view, until morning.
凶手能杀一个就能杀第二个
A killer will never hesitate to kill again.
这话我也会对安德烈伯爵夫妇说
I will convey the same message to the Andrenyis...
不管他们有没有外交豁免权
diplomatic immunity or not.
如果可以的话 我想看一下你们的护照
If I may, I will look at your passports.
我必须得找她谈谈
You know that I must talk with her.
你妻子的名字上有一块污渍
By the way, there is a grease spot on your wife's name.
你可能得看一下
You might want to look at that.
埃琳娜她不舒服
Elena is not well.
如果您不配合
If you do not permit me, your reluctance
我会把情况报告给南斯拉夫警方
will be noted to the Yugoslav Police...
相信他们一定会逮捕你们
and I have no doubt that they will arrest both you and...
你竟敢口出狂言
How dare you!
亲爱的
Darling!
Darling.
你的样子很滑稽 波洛先生
You are funny-looking, monsieur Poirot.
每个侦探都长得这么滑稽吗
Are all detectives so funny-looking?
抱歉 吵醒你了 伯爵夫人
I am sorry to wake you, Madame la Comtesse.
我晚上一般都醒着
I am always awake at night.
白天用来睡觉
In the day, I sleep.
有人害怕黑夜 而我却受不了阳光
Some fear darkness, but I cannot stand the light.
请问你是不是一直都在使用
You are always under the influence of...
巴比妥
Barbital.
巴比妥 巴比妥
Barbital, barbital.
大概都用了一卡车了吧
I take oceans of it.
说谎是没用的 亲爱的
Oh, there's no use in a lie, love.
他一眼就能看穿我们
He can see right through us.
没有它 我根本出不了门
I cannot go outside without it.
没有它 我连觉都睡不着
I cannot sleep without it.
我用它来克服恐惧
I take it against my fears.
你在害怕什么
What are you afraid of?
这一切
Everything.
你护照上写着 你娘家的姓氏是戈登伯格
Your passport has your maiden name as Goldenberg.
犹太人对吗
Jewish, yes?
血统并不纯正 我的中间名是玛利亚
Not so Jewish. My middle name isn't Maria.
你和你丈夫都是舞者吗
And you are a dancer like your husband?
不 他和我不一样
No, not like my husband.
我是芭蕾舞团的伴舞
Corps de ballet.
他是天生的舞蹈家
He is touched by angels.
而我只是一个靠
I have been shoved by passion
热情和磨练才勉强够格的人
and hard work to become adequate.
抱歉 我得回去躺着了
Excuse me, I must lie down again.
这是您唯一一件睡袍吗
Is this your only dressing gown?
我还有另一条 黄色的雪纺
No, I have another. Corn-colored chiffon.
我喜欢和侦探聊天
I like speaking to detectives.
你永远猜不到他们接下来会问什么
You never know what they're going to ask you next.
我知道很多国家的首都
I'm particularly good at capitals.
因为我的家庭教师教授地理课时非常严格
My governess was a stickler for geography.
你满意了吧
Are you satisfied?
确实如此 因为我看穿了一个谎言
I am always satisfied when I uncover a liar.
女士 你的名字不叫埃琳娜 应该是海伦娜
Madame, your name is not Elena. It is Helena.
尽管你们在护照和行李牌上
Despite your clumsy attempts
都动了手脚
to change it here and on your luggage.
我丈夫听说
My husband heard
你们找到一样证物
of a piece of evidence found...
一块绣了H字母的手帕
a handkerchief embroidered with an "H,"
他不想让我牵扯其中
and didn't want my "H" involved.
所以我们改了它 行李牌还有护照
So we changed it. The luggage and the passport.
远离是非应该算不上犯罪吧
It's no crime to want to be distant from trouble.
但是非就在眼前
Yet, here is trouble.
这起案子
A curious detail
一直围绕着阿姆斯特朗惨案
about the Armstrong tragedy at the heart of this case...
但令人费解的是 究竟有多少人 因此受到了伤害
is how many people were wounded by it.
一个是受害者的妹妹
The younger sister.
另一个是作为演员的母亲
The actress mother...
艺名叫做琳达·雅顿
stage name, Linda Arden.
我猜她应该也有犹太血统 犹太演员
I suppose she, too, was of Jewish ancestry...
通常不都会取艺名吗
as who is most likely to take a stage name?
所以是不是可以大胆地猜测
Is it too far to suggest...
她的本名正是戈登伯格
her original name was Goldenberg?
尤其当我看到眼前的这位年轻姑娘
Especially when we find a young woman,
她和演员的女儿
the same age...
年纪相仿
as her surviving daughter...
整天生活在恐惧之中
living in a world of fear?
她就是索尼娅的妹妹
The sister of Sonia Armstrong.
滚出去
Get out!
我听到了声音 就赶来了 没来晚吧
I hear noises and I run. Just in time, yes?
现在你该相信了吧 伯爵夫妇就是凶手
You must now believe the count and countess are the killers.
伯爵只是保护欲过强
The count is protective.
他夫人连打死只蜘蛛都不敢
The countess would no sooner kill a bedroom spider.
你不必装了
And you may desist with this charade.
你不是奥地利人 不是德国人 也不是教授
You are neither an Austrian, nor a German, nor a professor.
但你学得很像
But a good imitation.
是模仿你认识的某个人吗
Was it based on someone you know?
我老家有个屠夫是个德国佬
A local butcher where I grew up was a Kraut.
人很好 口音纯正
Good man, great accent.
你是怎么看出来的
What was it?
你说“都灵”的时候
You said "Tur-in..."
重音放错了地方
the emphasis on the wrong syllable
骄傲而又严谨的日耳曼人是不会
for a proud and proper Teuton.
读错重音的
"Tu-reen."
你真是太敏锐了 我算是服了
You are one sharp knife, I give you that.
奥地利教授 格哈德·哈德曼
Herr Professor Gerhard Hardman...
是个假身份
is my cover.
抱歉上演了一出种族歧视的戏码
I'm sorry about the colored folks cracks.
其实我自己也算半个犹太人
Hell, I'm half a Heeb myself.
塞勒斯·贝斯曼·哈德曼
Cyrus Bethman Hardman.
你是私家侦探
You are a Pinkerton detective?
做了三十年了
30 years.
当时我在伊斯坦布尔 刚刚结束工作
I was in Stamboul, coming back from a job,
公司就发电报给我
when the office cabled.
说雷切特想找个人保护他
Ratchett asked for a man to tail him,
出三倍价钱
offering triple time.
正好我就在附近
Lucky me being nearby.
他告诉我说
He told me to look out
要我留意一个矮个子尖嗓音的黑人
for a small, dark man with a high voice.
我从我的门缝里
I watched that hall...
盯着那条走廊整整一个晚上
all night through a crack in my door.
如果凶手出现的话
Any thug...
也会先经过我这里
had to go by me first.
我发誓是真的
I'll take my oath on it.
那你是不是也能发誓
And would you also take your oath...
自己真的做了三十年的私家侦探
on your thirty years as a Pinkerton Detective...
还是你又想骗我
or would you lie to me again...
否认自己曾经是一名警察的事实
and deny that you were, in fact, a policeman first?
你的枪 枪托上的格纹 蓝色的漆面
Your gun, the checkered grip, the blue finish...
显然是特制的警用左轮手枪
produced for the Police Positive edition.
1927年投入使用
1927 issue.
看来你准备了一箩筐
It appears there are no end to the lies
专门为我设计的谎言
manufactured just for me.
放下枪 你可以走了 教授
You can leave your gun as you go, Professor.
从他包厢的位置
From the position of his cabin...
不可能看不到凶手
it would have been impossible to miss.
除非雷切特的门当时是开着的
Unless Ratchett's door was open...
就像皮拉尔说的 她误打开过那扇门
as Pilar Estravados claims she opened it.
那样的话凶手就可能
In which case, someone could have been...
逃过他的视线
masked from his view.
我亲爱的凯瑟琳
My darling Katherine.
这是一起非常棘手的案子
This is an abominable crime...
而我却陷入了困境
and I am stuck, ma Katherine.
我找不到墙上的裂缝
I cannot find the crack in the wall.
他们中有人迷惑了我
Why does one of them elude me?
一直以来我都
I have always been...
非常自信
so sure.
太自信了
Too sure.
而现在的我
But now, I am very humble.
就像一个孩子 谦卑的说
And I say, like a little child...
我真的想不明白
I do not know.
我很怕 凯瑟琳
I am afraid, ma Katherine.
很抱歉 女士们先生们
My apologies, ladies and gentlemen.
列出重回轨道时
It is not safe on board
待在车厢里会有危险
whilst the engine is put back on the tracks.
我们去隧道里等候 谢谢
We are to wait in the tunnel. Thank you.
他们要把狗带去哪儿
Where are they taking the dogs?
它们会高兴的
They'll be happy.
这可不行
That's not right.
活动活动挺好的
Just to stretch their legs, it's good.
不  这么做不对
No, that's not right.
冻死了
It's freezing!
你找我
You asked for me?
又要审问了么
Another interrogation?
不 我喜欢和你聊天
Oh, no. I enjoy your company.
谢谢你 布克
Merci, Bouc.
请坐
Uh, please.
我列出了十个问题 还没找到答案
I have a list of ten questions I am no nearer to answering...
但火车马上要开了
and the train is about to leave.
你头脑敏锐
You have a clear mind...
说不准你会想到什么 请看
and I thought that you might produce an insight. Please.
手帕 烟斗通条
"The handkerchief. The pipe cleaner.
红色睡袍 制服
"The scarlet kimono. The uniform.
手表上的时间
"The time on the watch.
案发的时间 是之前还是之后
"Was he murdered then? Earlier or later?
一人还是多人作案
"By one person or more?
哪几位
"Which of them?"
抱歉 我帮不了你
Sorry, I can't help you.
谢谢
Uh... Merci.
或许还有第十一个问题
Perhaps there is an eleventh question
你没想到
you don't know to ask yet...
它能解决其他所有问题
that will give you the answer to the rest.
有可能
Perhaps.
其实我可以直接指控伯爵夫人
I could point an easy finger at the, uh, Countess Andrenyi.
我发现她是索尼娅·阿姆斯特朗的妹妹
I discovered she was Sonia Armstrong's sister.
你确定  是的
Are you certain? Yes.
可我猜她是无辜的
I suspect she may perhaps be innocent.
但只是猜测
Perhaps.
这趟列车上
But so many people have lied to me
有太多人对我撒谎了
on this train and do not seem to mind.
包括德贝汉小姐你在内也是如此
You yourself did so effortlessly.
我?
Me?
你说你从没去过美国
You told me you had never been to America.
你还隐瞒了一个事实
You also concealed the fact
悲剧发生时
that at the time of the tragedy...
你就住在阿姆斯特朗家里
you were living in the Armstrong household...
做他们女儿的家庭教师
as governess to their daughter.
整件事你很清楚
And you know this.
我也得过日子
I have my living to get.
一个女人牵扯上谋杀案
A girl detained in connection to a murder case...
就没有哪个正经人家敢请我了
no decent class family would engage me.
是你一手策划了雷切特的谋杀案
Miss Debenham, you planned Ratchett's murder.
你还叫来了伯爵夫人
And then you sent for the countess to witness it.
如果她看到他死了
If she saw him dead,
你认识的海伦娜就会回来
the Helena you knew might return.
你想等你的室友入睡 可她睡不着
You waited for your roommate to sleep, but she did not.
于是你就下药
You drugged her.
但药力只让她感到了头疼
But the barbital only gave her a headache.
列车靠站时 她出门要阿司匹林
She begged for an aspirin when the train stopped,
列车员去了站台
when the conductor was on the station...
周围终于没人了
when the coast was clear at last...
于是你偷偷溜进了
when you were allowed to enter
雷切特的房间
Ratchett's compartment, unseen.
你爱黛西·阿姆斯特朗 你杀了卡萨蒂
You loved Daisy Armstrong. You killed Cassetti.
卡萨蒂禽兽不如
Cassetti was a pig.
他死有余辜
He deserved to die.
人不是她杀的
She didn't kill him.
是我
I did.
玛丽 快走
Mary, go.
我一人做事
I can't let you take the blame...
一人当
for what I did alone.
玛丽 求你了 快走
Mary, please, go.
阿姆斯特朗是我最好的朋友
John Armstrong was my best friend,
我的指挥官
my commander.
他信任我
He believed in me.
他送我去了医学院 给了我未来
He sent me to medical school, gave me a future.
是卡萨蒂害死了他
Cassetti destroyed him.
我心情悲痛 结识了玛丽
In grief, I found Mary.
然后我找到了雷切特
Then I found Ratchett.
我们本想向警方揭发他 正如你之前听到的那样
Our plan was to reveal him to the police,
可我看到他那张脸
that's what you heard.
我知道
But when I saw his face...
他连上被告席的资格都没有
I knew he didn't deserve a trial.
所以你迷晕了麦奎因
So, you drugged MacQueen.
你调了手表上的时间
You changed the time on the watch...
这样你就能伪造雷切特的死亡时间了
so that you could lie about the time of death.
我不能让你指控玛丽
I couldn't let Mary be accused.
还有麦奎因
Or MacQueen.
我的罪孽应该由我一个人来赎
My sins are mine to pay for, alone.
我是个士兵
I'm a soldier.
士兵杀人是为了保护他人
A soldier kills to protect.
但现在 波洛先生
And now, Mr. Poirot,
我不得不保护我自己
I must protect myself from you.
为什么你还没死
Why aren't you dead yet?
波洛
Poirot?
先生们 请停下
Gentlemen, stop!
先生 我们得让所有乘客
Sir, we need to get all the passengers
回到车上去
back on the train.
你们先
You will retire...
别靠近列车
away from the train...
直到我叫你们过来
until I tell you to return.
你们满口谎言
You tell your lies...
以为没人会识破
and you think no one will know.
但至少会有两个人知道真相
But there are two people who will know.
对 两个人
Yes, two people.
你们的上帝
Your God...
还有我赫尔克里·波洛
and Hercule Poirot.
是时候结束这一切了
It is time to solve this case.
阿巴斯诺特医生刚才问为什么我还没死
Dr. Arbuthnot asked me why I was not yet dead.
他当然知道答案
He knew, of course, the answer.
那么近的距离神枪手会射偏吗
A sharpshooter who does not kill at close range?
刚才那枪不仅没有射偏 相反还很准
Your shot was not a mistake. It was a surgery.
你没杀我是因为你不是杀人犯
You could not kill me because you are no killer.
你们都不是杀人犯
None of you are killers.
但总得有这么一位凶手
And yet, someone must be.
这起案子可以有两种结论 第一种
There are two possible solutions to this crime.
很难 因为它最符合情理
One difficult, because it fits with most
但不是全部真相
but not all of the facts...
而另一个
and one more...
更复杂
complex.
第一个结论
The first solution.
雷切特有个仇家
Ratchett had enemies.
一个凶残的黑手党 趁医生他们下车时
A rogue Mafioso steals onto the train at Vinkovci...
在温科夫齐偷溜上了车
as MacQueen and Arbuthnot take the air.
穿着制服 拿着钥匙
Equipped with a uniform
捅死了雷切特
and a passkey, he stabs Ratchett.
再从哈伯德夫人的包厢逃走
He leaves through Mrs. Hubbard's compartment,
然后成功逃脱
and makes his escape.
不对
No.
不对 这根本说不通
No, no, no. It doesn't work.
为什么要藏起制服
Why hide the uniform, hmm?
谁迷晕了雷切特
Who drugs Ratchett?
又是谁刺伤了哈伯德夫人
Or stabs Mrs. Hubbard?
别胡扯
Damn it, man!
所以谁是最大的受益者
So I ask, who stands to benefit?
这起谋杀案的死者是一名杀人犯
This crime is the murdering of a murderer.
这么做或许是为了
The benefit is, perhaps...
在精神上 减轻痛苦
to the spirit, an ease of suffering.
为了赶走脑海中
To quiet a shouting voice
令人难以入眠的叫声
in the head that prevents sleep.
凶手就在我们之中
There is a murderer among us.
所以
So...
我们的阿巴斯诺特医生
We have Dr. Arbuthnot,
作为阿姆斯特朗上校最忠实的朋友
a dedicated, grateful friend to Colonel Armstrong.
他遇到了
He meets and finds solace
能带给他一丝安慰的家庭教师
in the company of the governess, Mary Debenham...
和黛西亲如母女的玛丽·德贝汉
who is almost like a mother to the little girl.
她还和索尼娅·阿姆斯特朗的妹妹 走得非常近
And so close to Mrs. Armstrong's young sister,
海伦娜·戈登伯格
Helena Goldenberg...
她嫁给了一个权贵
married to a powerful man
一个暴力而又易怒的男人
no stranger to rage and violence.
我们之中还有黛西的教母
We travel also with Daisy's godmother...
而这个人同样也是
to whom belongs...
我们在案发现场发现的
the monogrammed handkerchief
那条绣着字母手帕的主人
found at the scene of the crime.
上面的H 在俄语的字母表里面
The letter "H" in the Russian alphabet,
其实应该读作 N
of course, pronounced "N."
娜塔莉·德拉戈米罗夫
Natalia Dragomiroff.
而她这位对菜肴有着独到品味的女仆
And her devoted maid with a chef's eye?
在这之前是做什么的呢
Who was she before her current employ?
我猜她是阿姆斯特朗家的厨子
Might I suggest the Armstrongs' cook?
到这里故事还没有结束
But we are not yet done.
照顾黛西的那位保姆
The nurse in charge of Daisy...
出于内疚她从此信了教
her newfound religious zeal
因为她照看的孩子
born of guilt at allowing her charge...
被绑走了
to be abducted. It was you, was it not...
那天雷切特从窗户溜进去时
in her room the night when
你应该就在房里
Ratchett came in through the window?
那天晚餐
Did you have a glass of wine too many
你是不是多喝了一杯
with your supper that night?
因此你不断责怪自己不够警觉
Have you blamed yourself ever since...
所以才没能阻止他
for not being alert to stop him?
她是那么纯真 那么善良
She knew nothing but kindness...
那么可爱 可是
and love, until...
可是
until I...
我就不劳您费心了 先生
No need to divine with me, sir.
我是阿姆斯特朗上校一战时的勤务兵
I was Colonel Armstrong's batman in the war.
退伍后 我成了他在纽约的管家
And afterwards, his valet in New York.
他是天底下最高尚的人
As fine a man as God ever made.
他的司机也会这样说吧
Would his chauffeur agree?
正是上校的担保 他凭借银行的贷款
Was it a bank loan, secured by Armstrong,
建立起了自己的汽车帝国
allows him to build his automobile empire?
这份恩情永远还不清 还有谁最为可疑
He's indebted for life. Who else can we count?
这位私家侦探
What of the Pinkerton detective,
当年被指派负责
once a police officer...
阿姆斯特朗案的警官
assigned to the Armstrong case?
他对某人动了情
And he becomes attached to someone,
因为在当年的案件里 还有一个不为人知的受害者
for there is another, uncelebrated victim.
在那位女仆受到污蔑之前
You fell in love with the maid
你已经爱上了她
before she was falsely accused.
当你目睹了正义被人扭曲
You quit the police when you witnessed...
你选择了辞职
the travesty ofjustice...
当时麦奎因的父亲坚持要逮捕她
when MacQueen's father insisted on her arrest.
最后她选择了自杀
When she took her own life.
不
No! No, no!
苏珊为人非常温柔
Susanne was so gentle.
而她爱上了我
And she fell for me.
我头发都花白了
Old and already getting grey.
我劝她找一个更好的 可是
I told her she could do better...
她就是这样
but there she was...
每次约会都很准时
on time for every date.
为什么
Why else is a train...
大冬天列车还会客满 为什么伤口会深浅不一
so full in the dead of winter? Why the inconsistent wounds?
为什么会有那么多证物
Why the abundance of evidence? Why...?
为什么还有列车员
Why the conductor?
阿维尼翁的皮埃尔·米歇尔
Pierre Michel of Avignon...
失去了他的姐姐
who lost his sister...
被诬告的那名女仆
the accused maid...
苏珊·米歇尔
Susanne Michel.
只有一人 可以说
Only one soul can claim to have lost
比你们中任何人失去的都要多
more than any of you.
可怜的琳达·雅顿
The tragic Linda Arden...
索尼娅的母亲
mother of Sonia...
小黛西的外婆
grandmother of Daisy.
早已从舞台隐退
Retired from the stage...
但却献上了最后一场表演
but for one final performance.
你是个极其聪明的男人
You're an awfully clever man.
一起命案造成了一个生命的逝去
A murder should have one victim.
而当雷切特杀死了黛西·阿姆斯特朗的时候
When Ratchett kills Daisy Armstrong...
十几条生命随之破碎 扭曲 终结
a dozen lives are broken, deformed, ended.
他们要求正义
They demand justice!
尽管那么多受伤的灵魂 我们还是得找出
Of all these wounded souls, we must finally answer...
在他们之中 谁是凶手
who among them is a killer?
是谁拿起了刀子 答案就是
Who takes up the knife? The answer is...
凭一己之力是无法做到的
No single one of you could have done it.
两个人也不行
Nor any pair.
唯一的可能就是
It can only have been done...
你们所有人都参与了
by all of you.
你们所有人
Together.
突然的雪崩打乱了你们的计划
Even when the avalanche changes everything...
由于侦探的出现
as does the detective, plans must change.
计划必须改变 红色睡袍 还有制服
The kimono, the uniform.
出神入化的即兴表演
A remarkable improvisation,
以及一个知道如何避开要害的医生
the doctor who knows how to wound without killing.
每个人都扮演着一个角色
Each has their part to play.
动手
Do it.
全是我的计划
It was my plan.
是我找的他们
I recruited them.
我让哈德曼追查卡萨蒂的下落
I had Hardman track down Cassetti.
让麦奎因去替他工作
I sent MacQueen to work for him,
接着是马斯特曼
and then Masterman.
麦奎因可以安排
MacQueen could arrange
他在米歇尔当班时出行
he travel on the day that Michel was on duty.
雷切特先生
Mr. Ratchett?
没什么事
It's nothing.
好的先生 晚安
Bien, monsieur. Good night.
一切就这么完成了
And so it is done.
为了无辜的逝者
For the death of the innocent.
一命偿一命
A life for a life.
复仇
Revenge.
被绞死的应该是我 和他们无关
No one should hang for this but me.
是我一手策划的
It was my plan!
告诉警察是我一个人干的
Tell the police it was me, alone.
反正我早已经没有活下去的意义了
There's no life left in me anymore.
他们现在还有机会
They have a chance now.
海伦娜 我祈祷
Helena, I pray...
她应该还有机会
has a chance.
他们可以
They can...
继续生活
go live...
在某个地方
find some joy...
找到快乐
somewhere.
让我来结束这一切
Let it end with me.
他们不是杀人犯
They're not killers.
他们都是好人
They're good people.
他们可以继续做好人
They can be good again.
凡事要么是对的 要么是错的
There was right, there was wrong.
现在多了你们
Now there is you.
我无法做出判断
I cannot judge this.
由你们来决定
You must decide.
如果你们想逃避
You wish to go free
你们所犯下的罪行
without punishment for your crime...
那你们就得多杀一个人
then you must only commit one more.
我不会阻止你们
I will not stop you.
你不能让他们杀了你
You can't let them kill you.
你们把我的尸体扔进河里
You give my body to the lake,
这样就能清白的走出这个站台
and you walk away innocent at the station.
你们得封我的口
You must silence me.
布克可以说谎
Bouc can lie.
而我做不到
I cannot.
动手啊 谁都可以
Do it! One of you!
别乱来
Don't.
我的心早就跟着黛西一起死了
I already died with Daisy.
不
No!
你说你的职责是寻求正义
You said your role was to find justice.
在这儿什么才是正义
What is justice here?
有时光靠法律是远远不够的
Sometimes, the law of man is not enough.
良知又该置于何处
Where does conscience lie?
和黛西一起埋葬了
Buried with Daisy.
亲爱的阿姆斯特朗上校
My dear Colonel Armstrong.
终于 我可以给你回信了
Finally, I can answer your letter...
至于我脑海中的想法
at least with the thoughts in my head
以及我内心的感受
and the feeling in my heart...
在某个地方 你一定听得到
that somewhere, you can hear me.
我现在已经揭开了
I have now discovered
案件的真相
the truth of the case, and it is...
结果让人十分不安
profoundly disturbing.
我见识了人性的破碎
I have seen the fracture of the human soul.
那么多不幸的人生 那么多的痛苦和愤怒
So many broken lives, so much pain and anger...
被心底深处的那份悲痛所支配着
giving way to the poison of deep grief...
直到一起罪行引发了连锁反应
until one crime became many.
我一直都愿意相信
I have always wanted to believe
人类是理性并且文明的
that man is rational and civilized.
我的存在正是基于这份信念
My very existence depends upon this hope...
加上我看事物独到的方法 以及我的那点脑细胞
upon order and method and the little gray cells.
但现在或许
But now, perhaps, I am asked...
我需要转变一下
to listen, instead...
听从我的心声
to my heart.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
通过这起案子我意识到 正义的天平
I have understood in this case that the scales of justice...
未必能永远保持平衡
cannot always be evenly weighed.
而这也让我头一次学会了
And I must learn, for once...
去接受这个世界的不平衡
to live with the imbalance.
车上没有杀人犯
There are no killers here.
只有值得好好活下去的人
Only people who deserve a chance to heal.
警方已经接受了
The police have accepted
我的第一种结论
my first solution to the crime...
凶手单独作案并且成功逃逸
the lone assassin who made his escape.
我现在要下车去办结案手续了
I will leave the train here to conclude formalities.
你们都可以离开了
You are all free to go.
希望你们能就此获得安宁
And may you find your peace with this.
希望我们都能如此
May we all.
您好
Hello.
我在找一位叫波洛的先生
I'm looking for a Mr. Poirot.
有紧急事件要找他
He's needed on a very urgent matter.
他正在休假
Ah. He is on holiday.
又是卡斯纳的案子
The, uh, Kassner case again?
不 先生 更糟糕
No, sir, far worse.
我必须得马上带他去埃及
I have to take him to Egypt straight away.
那儿发生了一起谋杀案 在该死的尼罗河上
There's been a murder, sir, right on the bloody Nile.
您就是那位侦探吗
Are you the detective?
是的
Yes.
我就是那个侦探
I am the detective.
你可以把领带摆正吗
Could you please straighten your tie?
一会儿车上见
I will see you at the car.